<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Bridget Kromhout]]></title>
  <link href="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-04T08:46:38-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bridget Kromhout]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The First Rule of DevOps Club]]></title>
    <link href="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2014/11/03/the-first-rule-of-devops-club/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-03T20:25:18-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2014/11/03/the-first-rule-of-devops-club</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Heard last week at <a href="http://devopsdays.org/events/2014-belgium/">devopsdays in Ghent, Belgium</a>:</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m just in marketing, so I don&rsquo;t count.&rdquo; <br>
&ldquo;I&rsquo;m just a student, so I don&rsquo;t have anything to add.&rdquo; <br>
&ldquo;I&rsquo;m just a developer, so I don&rsquo;t really devops.&rdquo; <br>
&ldquo;I&rsquo;m not really in the devops tribe; I&rsquo;m just on the outskirts, but I&rsquo;m trying.&rdquo;<br></p>

<p>Whenever I thought to, I tried to assert both in word and deed that the speaker is in the club. They&rsquo;re participating at a devopsdays; they belong.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><a href="https://twitter.com/davemangot">Dave Mangot</a> gave <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/dmangot/the-cognitve-neuroscience-of-empathy-youre-a-devops-natural">an interesting cognitive neuroscience talk</a> at this devopsdays wherein he mentioned in-groups and out-groups, and said that from a neurons-firing perspective, we have a greater capacity for empathy with those we see as &ldquo;like us&rdquo; than those we see as &ldquo;the other&rdquo;.</p>

<p>This is an evolutionary characteristic of the human brain. It doesn&rsquo;t make us bad people if we think in terms of  &ldquo;us&rdquo; and &ldquo;them&rdquo; &ndash; it makes us homo sapiens, not that far removed from the savanna and the tribal group that protected us.</p>

<p>Going to a devopsdays, especially one with so many familiar faces from my tribe, is pretty awesome. It feels good to belong. And I gotta tell you, it feels pretty shitty to think you belong and then find yourself in an out-group again. Still.</p>

<p>Some of you are thinking, &ldquo;What are you talking about, Bridget? You have pink hair and spoke at like a dozen conferences in the last year and run Docker in production. Surely you never feel like you don&rsquo;t belong in the hipster devopserati.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Yeah. Except for all the time. Like when I&rsquo;m in a group of my peers and they casually talk about ops guys. Those ops guys are so smart. We need more of those ops guys, so we should interview some &ndash; maybe Python guys! or really brilliant monitoring guys! &ndash; and the guys we have will know more great guys to hire. Maybe even those kernel guys or other smart guys who contribute to open-source projects. Maybe a golang guy, or a guy with a really epic Proud Unix Beard. Because guys guys guys.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t have all that much to say about Being A Woman In Tech. I&rsquo;ve only got so much time and attention to spend, and I&rsquo;d much rather spend it on things where I&rsquo;m learning something new. (In a revelation that will shock precisely no one, I already know what it&rsquo;s like to be a me-shaped human working in tech.) So I&rsquo;ll direct your attention to <a href="http://modelviewculture.com">Model View Culture</a> or the <a href="http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/Geek_Feminism_Wiki">Geek Feminism Wiki</a> if you want to read nuanced, well-constructed writing about the intersection between feminism and tech.</p>

<p>Every once in a while, though, I need to say something. Last summer after hearing one &ldquo;ops guys&rdquo; too many, I tweeted about it:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en" align="center"><a href="https://twitter.com/bridgetkromhout/status/483350276540080129"></a></blockquote>


<br>


<p>In discussions on twitter, I pointed folks to <a href="http://jvns.ca/blog/2013/12/27/guys-guys-guys/">an informal polling of the twitterverse Julia Evans did last year on the topic of gender-specificity in language</a>. It&rsquo;s hilarious and you should read it.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/images/python-guys.png" title="Python guys" alt="Example from the blog of Julia Evans"></p>

<p>Right about now, we probably need to #include &lt;std-disclaimer.h>. I had my mind blown <a href="http://bridgetkromhout.com/speaking/2014/devopsdays-belgium/">researching surrealist art</a> recently, and learned that René Magritte saw labels as arbitrary. &ldquo;An image is not so wedded to its name,&rdquo; he said, &ldquo;that one cannot find another which suits it better.&rdquo;  So yes, I know, meaning is assigned arbitrarily. Language is mutable. Oceania has always been at war with Eastasia. Systemd is a floor wax <em>and</em> a dessert topping. We aren&rsquo;t all going to agree, and that&rsquo;s okay.</p>

<p>I cannot speak for all women ever, or for all women in tech, or for all women in operations. I&rsquo;m mostly just an expert at being me-in-tech. I can definitely tell you that when &ldquo;ops guys&rdquo; is the generic, I feel like I&rsquo;m in the out-group.</p>

<p>And judging by the number of times in the last twenty years that I&rsquo;ve had to pinky-swear that I&rsquo;m really, truly an actualfax sysadmin and would you like my opinions on FreeBSD for your NFS server instead of Linux (because lolTCPstack, amirite?), I think a lot of people&rsquo;s &ldquo;ops default&rdquo; is set to look more like this:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/images/real-ops.png" width="480" title="Real Ops" alt="Mitchell Hashimoto with a glass of wine"></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/mitchellh">Mitchell Hashimoto</a> is amazing and everyone should be paying attention to <a href="https://www.hashicorp.com">HashiCorp</a>. But when I got a still from <a href="http://vimeo.com/42882124">his Real Ops video</a> during Belgium&rsquo;s Ignite Karaoke, my immediate reaction was, &ldquo;<a href="http://www.ustream.tv/recorded/54697834">I&rsquo;ve got news for you. Real ops look like me.</a>&rdquo; (Patently untrue given the makeup of the audience, but it got some impromptu mid-Ignite applause anyhow.)</p>

<p>I thought that was going to be the only thing I said on the subject. But when the open space opening the next day had an anecdote featuring &ldquo;ops guys&rdquo;, I&rsquo;d had enough. I went up, took the mic, and told the audience of several hundred people (of whom perhaps 98% were guys) how erased I feel when I hear that.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en" align="center"><a href="https://twitter.com/zipkid/status/527103793717321728"></a></blockquote>


<br>


<p>I said what I always think (and sometimes say) when this comes up. If you are a guy, and you like to date women, would you place a personal ad that says this? &ldquo;I&rsquo;d like to meet a wonderful guy to fall in love and spend my life with. This guy must like long walks on the beach and holding hands, and must also be female.&rdquo; If that sounds ludicrous to you, then you don&rsquo;t actually think &ldquo;guy&rdquo; is gender-neutral.</p>

<p>Someone asked what we should say instead of &ldquo;ops guys&rdquo;, and I suggested ops team, ops people, ops engineers, ops folks, or just &ldquo;the devs and the ops&rdquo;.</p>

<p>So, yeah. There are not a lot of women in ops at the moment (understatement). If you want us to stick around, and if you want there to ever be more, choosing language that makes room for us to be part of the in-group is as good a place to start as any.</p>

<p>In later discussion, <a href="https://twitter.com/mindweather">Dave Zwieback</a> called me brave. Not so sure about that; maybe I&rsquo;m just foolhardy. I know the internets are not kind to uppity women with <em>opinions</em>. (See also: everything ever.) But I couldn&rsquo;t remain silent in that moment. I tried hard to make it not a direct attack on the speaker, telling him that it&rsquo;s not just him; I hear it everywhere, all the time, in the US.</p>

<p>I know I did make some people uncomfortable. I do not want them to have to feel that way; I know all too well how that feels. But I did want them to hear, and to know. (Some, including the very responsive and understanding speaker, gathered immediately afterwards for an impromptu open space on the topic, which was great.)</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve talked about inclusiveness in our conference community before. <a href="http://www.mattstratton.com/devops/hipster-devops-happens-to-the-best-of-us">Matt Stratton</a> and <a href="https://www.usenix.org/blog/navigating-conferences-unusual-attendee">Katherine Daniels</a> have blogged about it recently.) This week, I saw action along those lines. <a href="https://twitter.com/nathenharvey">Nathen Harvey</a> held an &ldquo;Ask Me Anything&rdquo; open space where any question was okay, and people asked about jargon and how to become a conference speaker, things that might not have seemed accessible to them before. I was really happy to see <a href="https://twitter.com/mfdii">Michael Ducy</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/chriswiggy">Chris Jackson</a> step up to the stage in Ghent and publicly correct themselves to ensure they were being as inclusive as they could. I can&rsquo;t recall having ever seen that before at a tech event; it heralds a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sea_change_(idiom)">sea change</a>. We are taking iterative improvement seriously in our culture as well as in our tools.</p>

<p>As for those conversations I had at devopsdays with the folks who thought they were &ldquo;just&rdquo; not devops enough? I told the marketing person that ops needs marketing; very few people know that operations is a thing that exists in the world, let alone aspire to be one of us. I asked the student for insights as to what was the most interesting from a fresh perspective. I thanked the developer for tools, because we in ops need tools. I told the big-company person that he belonged, and encouraged him to claim space and have his voice heard.</p>

<p>We aren&rsquo;t well served when our community is segmented into the hipsters versus the enterprise, the PowerShell wizards versus those who perennially believe it&rsquo;s finally the year of Linux on the desktop, the web-scale cowboy devs versus the ops chicks who hate MongoDB, and all those other inflection points where we differ from one another.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll do better to focus on the ways we are the same. All of us in this devops space are interested in improving our workflows and our interactions with our co-workers, no matter what our specific job functions are. We all want to be fast and flexible, well-informed and well-supplied with the tools of our trade. We all want to be proud of what we accomplish and happy in the company of the people with whom we accomplish it. We all want the product of our efforts to work well (whether we define &ldquo;well&rdquo; as features, stability, or both). We can use those commonalities to trick our medial prefrontal cortex into empathy with those erstwhile &ldquo;others&rdquo;.</p>

<p>The first rule of devops club is welcome to the club.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four Interactions That Could Have Gone Better]]></title>
    <link href="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2014/09/22/four-interactions-that-could-have-gone-better/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-22T16:50:21-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2014/09/22/four-interactions-that-could-have-gone-better</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I go to a lot of tech events, which means I meet a lot of people in tech. Most of you won&rsquo;t be surprised to find out that many of them are dudes, and awesome dudes at that. And way more frequently than I&rsquo;d like, I also find myself in the most <em>tedious</em> conversations.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re wondering why women don&rsquo;t attend the conferences, unconferences, meetups, or hackathons you enjoy, or why you don&rsquo;t seem to make meaningful professional connections with the ones who are there, maybe they&rsquo;ve been having these conversations often enough that they&rsquo;re tired of it, and would rather spend their time doing <em>anything else at all</em>.</p>

<p>So, here are four recent real-life examples of opening lines that didn&rsquo;t start off the interactions in the best way, followed by four ways I think they could have gone better. Not a comprehensive list, because none of us have that much time. :)</p>

<!-- more -->


<hr />

<p><p></p>

<p><strong>1. &ldquo;Are you an engineer?&rdquo;</strong></p>

<p>Those were his introductory words after looking me down and up and down a couple of times, and my impulsive answer was to laugh aloud. Nope, not my most empathy-filled moment, and I don&rsquo;t recommend that approach. I felt impatient to be fielding a question that sounded like an incredulous &ldquo;what are you doing at this industry-company afterparty?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Why&rsquo;s that so funny?&rdquo; he wanted to know, honestly perplexed.</p>

<p>I looked at his badge and said, &ldquo;It just is. <code>&lt;Name&gt;</code>, are <em>you</em> an engineer?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Um, yes.&rdquo; He seemed a bit confused. To be fair, he couldn&rsquo;t have been mistaken for anything but. He had a classic geek aesthetic, straight out of central casting. Nobody would ever question his plausibility in the role of Resident Computer Guy.</p>

<p>I pressed on. &ldquo;Has anyone else at this conference asked you if you&rsquo;re an engineer?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;No&hellip;&rdquo; And then he brightened, an idea occurring to him. &ldquo;But you&rsquo;re wearing a company t-shirt, and that usually means marketing or recruiter!&rdquo;</p>

<p>I lifted my badge and pointed to the &ldquo;Speaker&rdquo; line. &ldquo;Or an operations engineer wearing her company&rsquo;s shirt the day she&rsquo;s speaking at the conference.&rdquo; Gently, with a smile, I then made polite small talk about him and his job until the bartender could give me the water I&rsquo;d come to get. Although unintentionally hilarious, he seemed to be a nice enough guy, and we managed an okay chat of the Fight Club single-serving-friends sort. So I wasn&rsquo;t offended, just eyerolly on the inside (and okay, a bit on the outside too).</p>

<p>And then I excused myself to go back to hanging out with Team Etsy, who don&rsquo;t tend to ask such facepalm-inducing questions. I&rsquo;m extroverted and I like meeting new people at conferences, but when I don&rsquo;t have the energy to put up with possible negative interactions, I&rsquo;ll trade variety for a known-good. I don&rsquo;t enjoy interacting with peers who act like I am The Mysterious Other and Definitely Not One of Them. It&rsquo;s tiresome every time it happens again. Still.</p>

<p><strong>2. &ldquo;Wanna go to the titty bar with us?&rdquo;</strong></p>

<p>On my way into a conference hotel one evening, I heard the word &ldquo;devops&rdquo; coming from the bar, so I walked in and said, &ldquo;Hi! Sounds like you&rsquo;re with the conference; heard you talking devops&rdquo; to three guys in a conversation there. As opening salvos go, their response gets points for being direct (and succinct; they didn&rsquo;t even introduce themselves). I noped my way out of that conversation right quick, saying, &ldquo;no thanks; you gentlemen have fun&rdquo;. (It&rsquo;s possible there were detectable levels of snark, because what kind of question is that for someone you&rsquo;ve just met? I don&rsquo;t personally care what they got up to, but that&rsquo;s rather awkward. I&rsquo;ll leave it to the reader to judge or not judge their choices.) I then left the hotel bar and ran into a Twitter friend in the lobby, and while I was chatting with him, the three drunk attendees came lurching after me. (They were definitely with our conference; one was even wearing the conference t-shirt.)</p>

<p>They tried convincing both of us to join them, and (being sober) I made my saving throw to dodge an Axe Body Spray-scented attempted hug. I then excused myself and headed to my room, while apparently they kept following my Twitter friend and hassling him to go with them for a few more minutes.</p>

<p>(I&rsquo;m all for #hugops, but personally I&rsquo;d rather have learned your name or at least Twitter handle before we are #hugops buddies. And other women might feel very differently! You should have a verbal ACK that hugging is welcomed by an individual woman before you attempt it, or better yet, let her initiate any hugging. #hugops is a TCP-based not a UDP-based protocol.)</p>

<p>I never felt threatened or particularly alienated; I was heading up to bed anyhow. But if I&rsquo;d wanted to stay there and keep interacting with other conference-goers, those dudes were a deterrent; if I were a different person with a different set of lived experiences, this could have hit me very differently. It seems they&rsquo;d completely missed the point of the conference&rsquo;s code of conduct; I&rsquo;m pretty sure that wasn&rsquo;t the kind of inclusiveness it encouraged. And sure, there are much worse things they could have said or done. But when one dude said and did this relatively minor stuff, his two buddies thought it was peachy-keen. Not a sign of good peer review there.</p>

<p><strong>3. &ldquo;Do you know who that obscure sci-fi character is, the one you used in your slide deck?&rdquo;</strong></p>

<p>I know a fair number of conference speakers. Some need to hide before and/or after speaking. Some head right to the bar afterwards. Some thrive in the spotlight of &ldquo;office hours&rdquo; after a talk, engaging one-to-one with all comers. Many of us seem to finish our slides on the plane if not the podium. I haven&rsquo;t yet met one who puts stuff generated by /dev/random into a deck without being motivated by any context or reason.</p>

<p>If you want to talk about that TV show you love, don&rsquo;t open with a line that sounds like you&rsquo;re <a href="http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/Fake_geek_girls">fake-geek-girling</a> the speaker who just got off-stage. Because it&rsquo;s entirely possible that she taped the entire run of that series on VHS, can recite key passages, and rewrote one of the tie-in novels because she didn&rsquo;t like the ending.</p>

<p>Again, a nice guy. Probably meant well. But in those fraught moments right after public speaking, being asked if they understand their own slides is not a conversation opener that any presenter I know would enjoy.</p>

<p><strong>4. &ldquo;I didn&rsquo;t understand most of that stuff you just said about AWS infrastructure tradeoffs. But could you design my app?&rdquo;</strong></p>

<p>Design is a fantastic skill that I do not even remotely possess. Seriously, I could design you something awesome&hellip; as long as I could do it with awk or sed, and you&rsquo;re okay with it looking like <a href="http://nethack.org/common/index.html">nethack</a>.</p>

<p>This isn&rsquo;t even the first time I&rsquo;ve been asked if I&rsquo;m a designer. At least this guy didn&rsquo;t insist that I <em>must</em> be, because I look &ldquo;artistic&rdquo; (by which I can only guess the previous guy saying that meant &ldquo;female&rdquo;). (Yes, I have brightly-colored plastic hair extensions. I hire a stylist with actual taste to help me with that!)</p>

<p>The important thing is, when a woman says, &ldquo;nope, can&rsquo;t design stuff for you; I&rsquo;m an operations engineer&rdquo;, you should believe her. Or, you know, stop assuming that every woman you meet is going to map to the roles held by women you&rsquo;ve met in the past.</p>

<p>Also, I suspect nobody would claim to be in ops were it not true, since it would take about ten seconds to unravel such a deception; not to mention, most people don&rsquo;t even know operations is a thing that exists in the world. Maybe we need our friends in design to help with some promo materials!</p>

<hr />

<p><p>
<strong>So, how could these interactions be better?</strong></p>

<p>You are probably already pretty good at talking about tech and geeking out about the stuff you love. Hooray! Chances are decent that when you meet a woman at a tech event, she might be into tech too!</p>

<p>And hey, the above four examples could annoy people who aren&rsquo;t women too. This isn&rsquo;t specific to gender relations or intentional discrimination; it&rsquo;s about making choices that limit (or enhance!) the quality of your potential interactions with your fellow techies.</p>

<p>So, here are four approaches to try instead:</p>

<p><strong>1. Ask open-ended questions that don&rsquo;t make assumptions. </strong></p>

<p><em>Instead of asking her if she&rsquo;s an engineer or assuming she&rsquo;s a recruiter or in marketing, ask her, &ldquo;What are you enjoying doing at Company X?&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>She might have a hilarious table-flip anecdote about MongoDB or fresh insights into some Docker thing you&rsquo;ve been wanting to try. Give her room to surprise you; open-ended questions lead to better conversational outcomes in most circumstances no matter who&rsquo;s involved. And hey, most companies are hiring; if hers sounds cool, maybe you&rsquo;ll be interested in talking to them. Or if she doesn&rsquo;t sound like she&rsquo;s having fun at her current gig, maybe your company can poach her!</p>

<p><strong>2. Be as respectful as you would be to any person, regardless of their gender. </strong></p>

<p><em>Please, thank you, not interrupting (or at least asking if it&rsquo;s okay to page her out to disk!): you probably went to kindergarten; you know this stuff.</em></p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re thinking, &ldquo;I would never say something horrifyingly rude and sexist! I am unfailingly polite to women!&rdquo;, you still might be making women uncomfortable.</p>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t know a woman well enough to know how she feels about these things, I wouldn&rsquo;t suggest pulling out a chair for her, kissing her hand, saying &ldquo;ladies first&rdquo;, offering to protect her from amorphous threats, commenting on her attractiveness, or calling her &ldquo;madame&rdquo;/&ldquo;m&#8217;lady&rdquo;. What reads as polite to some might read as condescending to others, and definitely could be seen as setting her apart from the men you consider to be your equals. Leave the chivalry at home.</p>

<p>One place you can help, though: like the gentlemen above who could have peer-reviewed their friend, you can say something to the guys around you, so that they&rsquo;ll know that you value when they act respectful too. (Woman can say this stuff, but the guys who are less-aware are probably more likely to listen to other guys anyhow.)</p>

<p><strong>3. Talk about the event you&rsquo;re both at without challenging her right to be there or implying that she needs to provide bona fides. </strong></p>

<p><em>Instead of asking why she&rsquo;s attending or what she&rsquo;s doing there, ask her, &ldquo;What are you the most interested in learning at this conference? Are there particular speakers you&rsquo;re looking forward to hearing?&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>Tell her about something you&rsquo;ve enjoyed at the event and ask her what she&rsquo;s found interesting. (Yes, instead of first quizzing/judging her as to which track(s) she&rsquo;s attended, offer her some kind of conversational hook. You know perfectly well that the hallway track is a valid track! And that goes doubly for the Werewolf track.) This will help you welcome any new attendees, not just the ones who identify as women.</p>

<p><strong>4. Treat her as an individual. </strong></p>

<p><em>Address her as &ldquo;you&rdquo; and ask her opinion, not the opinion of a hypothetical &ldquo;someone like you&rdquo;.</em></p>

<p>She may be there representing her organization, but she probably didn&rsquo;t come prepared to represent 51% of the entire US population (or whatever the percentage breakdown is, where you are). Asking a woman you just met about Being A Woman places an unwelcome burden on her, one where she needs to play the role of &ldquo;Representative Woman In Tech&rdquo; for the 10,000th time instead of being seen as a person in her own right.</p>

<p>It would be pretty strange if every guy in tech you met were exactly the same as all the others. And that goes for women as well! Giving people space to be themselves allows you the chance to get to know them, which is awesome.</p>

<p>(And it&rsquo;s possible she doesn&rsquo;t want to be described with the noun &ldquo;a female&rdquo;, which evokes a Discovery-channel-like narrative of the female of the species approaching the watering hole, her calf hidden safely in the underbrush. Go with &ldquo;woman&rdquo; if you feel the need to point out the obvious.)</p>

<hr />

<p><p>
If you&rsquo;re recognizing your own past behaviour in any of the above, congrats! That means that you have enough self-awareness to realize that you might have inadvertently made a woman in tech feel like you don&rsquo;t see her as a peer. Awareness is the first step towards change, whether you become aware during an interaction or while reading a blog post. (The next step is trying out the improved interactions. Iteration is a thing! Perhaps you&rsquo;ll see better results!)</p>

<p>I love working in tech, and I want to be able to encourage other women in tech without a bajillion caveats about all the things they&rsquo;ll deal with constantly. Plus, if you create a positive culture that welcomes new, different, or marginalized individuals, everyone will want to work at your org. Which is probably hiring. Win!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[All That Sparkles Is Not Magic]]></title>
    <link href="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2014/07/20/all-that-sparkles-is-not-magic/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-20T00:35:38-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2014/07/20/all-that-sparkles-is-not-magic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On February 20th I emailed Michael Ducy, one of our local devops meetup organizers, and agreed to be the head organizer for devopsdays Minneapolis. The conference occurred July 17-18. Protip: 147 days isn&rsquo;t as long as you&rsquo;d think listening to Spike&rsquo;s monologue in early BtVS S6. (We&rsquo;re all nerds here, right?)</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I reached out to Mike Rembetsy who&rsquo;d done a bang-up job with devopsdays New York, and when pondering his helpful advice I realized that, like him, I needed a great team. If you were at the conference or watching the livestream you saw some of these folks on camera introducing others and facilitating Open Space; others worked behind the scenes with sponsors, on the evening social mixer, on all the details needed for smooth operation of an event. Donnie Berkholz, Marisa Brandt, Andy Domeier, Michael Ducy, Tom Duffield, Tony Notto, and Jeff Williams did a fabulous job!</p>

<p>Our speakers hit on themes of empathy &amp; inclusion, organizational communication, respecting commitments, the relationship between tools and culture, processing failure, the future and the past. I&rsquo;m incredibly grateful to all our speakers whether they came by bicycle from Northeast Minneapolis or by wide-body jet from Belgium. With humor and honesty, the longer sessions and Ignites alike gave us a catalyst to launch dozens of Open Space discussions. Most of the talks have slides posted already and video will be coming shortly; both are or will be linked from each talk&rsquo;s description on the <a href="http://devopsdays.org/events/2014-minneapolis/program/">devopsdays Minneapolis 2014 program page</a>.</p>

<p>At the beginning of the conference, I asked how many present were participating in their first devopsdays, and a vast majority of the perhaps 250 people in the room raised their hands. Based on everything I&rsquo;ve heard in person and read on Twitter, it seems that many people found it to be a valuable and thought-provoking experience. When Patrick Debois asked me to define a victory condition, I said that I wanted everyone to have a fabulous time, learn lots of things, take them back to their organizations, and be the better for it. I&rsquo;m hopeful we&rsquo;ll hear that&rsquo;s happening!</p>

<p>Our opening keynote speaker Sascha Bates talked about how &ldquo;hipster devops&rdquo; that excludes people isn&rsquo;t what we want to be doing, and on day two I got valuable feedback from a marvelously honest attendee that gave me the opportunity to course-correct a bit and try even harder to make sure everyone felt included. A little over a year ago I was the one new to this whole devops thing, this exhilarating space. I want to keep a gap in the conversation circle open to allow more people to join in. I&rsquo;m so excited that more people in my local tech community are interested in this cultural shift (and yes, willing to put up with all the jargon and in-jokes that any community amasses &ndash; perhaps all the goat and silo stuff amuses those from out-state).</p>

<p>In his closing keynote, Patrick Debois posed intriguing philosophical questions; one that&rsquo;s stuck with me (roughly paraphrased) is, when we up-end the apple cart and jump into something like &ldquo;devops&rdquo;, what have we lost? I think that if we pause, we reflect, we open our minds and listen, we can accumulate wisdom in striated layers, not washing away the old with the new, but layering upon it. In places, the foundations of older frameworks and practices may be evident, may peek out and glint in the sun. And everywhere, we stand on the solid shoulders of giant horses that may sparkle (I mentioned sun! Minneapolis weather was perfect last week) but definitely aren&rsquo;t unicorns.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
