<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Bridget Kromhout]]></title>
  <link href="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-19T16:21:20+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bridget Kromhout]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tl;dr: Your Talk Is Accepted]]></title>
    <link href="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2016/04/06/tl-dr-your-talk-is-accepted/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-06T18:42:19+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2016/04/06/tl-dr-your-talk-is-accepted</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;<em>stretching out and touching the unknown, the real unknown, the unknown unknown.</em>&rdquo;<br>
&mdash; D.H. Lawrence</p>

<p>Much like knowing the right keywords to google when troubleshooting, it takes experience to know the right questions to ask when speaking at a conference. We encourage new speakers at devopsdays Minneapolis, which means I attempt to present all speakers with answers to questions they haven&rsquo;t asked.</p>

<p>This year, I started writing the email for our speakers, and it got <em>long</em>. I decided that nobody would read that long a narrative, and broke it down into bolded sections and numbered lists labeled by when they require action.</p>

<p>&ldquo;A+++ excellent email. You&rsquo;ve done this before, I can see,&rdquo; said our closing keynote speaker <a href="https://twitter.com/mipsytipsy">Charity Majors</a>. She later added, &ldquo;And one well-formatted email is so much easier to keep track of than half a dozen.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Trufax! I&rsquo;m going to keep improving it; meanwhile, I&rsquo;m posting this to inspire other organizers with what info to provide, and to help other speakers know what to ask.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>devopsdays Minneapolis 2016 speaker acceptance letter, annotated</h2>

<blockquote><p>Dear “Name”,</p>

<p>Thank you for proposing to give this presentation:</p>

<p>“Title”</p>

<p>It has been accepted as one of the 30-minute talks for devopsdays Minneapolis 2016. (<a href="http://devopsdays.org/events/2016-minneapolis/">http://devopsdays.org/events/2016-minneapolis/</a>)</p></blockquote>

<p>You can check out the <a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/events/2016-minneapolis/program/">devopsdaysMSP 2016 program</a> to see the eight people who got this email.</p>

<p>This language varied a little bit for the invited keynotes, and I&rsquo;m noticing now that this is the only place where I talk about the timeslot. I could clarify that if they want to take Q&amp;A (which is optional) that it will fit inside the 30 minutes.</p>

<p>And yes, I am being clear about which conference I&rsquo;m writing to them about. Some people submit the same talk to multiple conferences, and even to multiple devopsdays conferences.</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>What you need to do right now:</strong></p>

<p>1) Reply to this email and confirm that<br>
  a) you will be present to give this talk in Minneapolis, July 20-July 21 2016<br></p></blockquote>

<p>Due to job changes or scheduling issues, sometimes a speaker needs to decline! Wouldn&rsquo;t want to list them as participating and then need to amend it.</p>

<blockquote><p>  b) you consent to your presentation being recorded and published<br></p></blockquote>

<p>Never been an issue for us, but might as well make sure.</p>

<blockquote><p>  c) you have read and will follow the code of conduct<br></p></blockquote>

<p>If a speaker is against codes of conduct, I want to find that out before I put their name on our website. That&rsquo;s not a point of view I&rsquo;m interested in featuring on our stage.</p>

<blockquote><p>You have until Friday April 8th, 2016 at 5pm Central time to confirm those three things via a reply to this email. If we do not hear from you by then, we will regrettably need to rescind this offer and invite an alternate speaker.</p></blockquote>

<p>You don&rsquo;t want to leave uncertainty about how long an offer&rsquo;s valid for. (Obviously it&rsquo;s not valid <em>forever</em> since the conference will happen someday, so it&rsquo;s just a question of how long you can realistically wait before moving on.)</p>

<blockquote><p>2) Give me any desired edits for your talk description &amp; bio, which we&rsquo;ll be listing on the website:</p>

<p>“Description”</p>

<p>“Bio”</p></blockquote>

<p>We asked for these at talk submission time. We aren&rsquo;t set up well to add speaker headshots until we finish some site updates, so we didn&rsquo;t request those. We would have requested Twitter handles at this point, except I&rsquo;d already tracked them all down.</p>

<p>In some cases I suggested edits here, whether it was to remove unintentionally problematic or confusing language, to strengthen the title, or to better fit the description to a single-track conference. I don&rsquo;t appreciate when someone edits my title, description, or bio without consulting me, so I don&rsquo;t do that.</p>

<blockquote><p>3) Wait until we post the schedule before you announce that you&rsquo;re speaking, as not every proposal submitter has heard back yet. We intend on posting the schedule to the devopsdays.org site in the next week or so. We will tweet about it from @devopsdaysmsp when it&rsquo;s up.</p></blockquote>

<p>It&rsquo;s no fun finding out you&rsquo;re not speaking by seeing a schedule you&rsquo;re not on or by seeing happy tweets from accepted speakers while you&rsquo;re still waiting to hear. So we accept talks, get confirmation that they&rsquo;re still possible, and then send regrets to the speakers whose talks we can&rsquo;t take. Only then do we publish the schedule.</p>

<blockquote><p>4) Let me know what kind of phone you have (iOS, Android, etc) &ndash; this is for a small gift we’re planning to give you as a token of our appreciation.</p></blockquote>

<p>Most people missed this question, and no wonder; with the talk description and bio filled in, they didn&rsquo;t scroll down, assuming there was nothing else they needed to do in this section. Lesson learned; I&rsquo;ll move this last bit that needs an answer to ahead of the material their eyes will skim over.</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>What you should do before archiving this email:</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>This stuff, they don&rsquo;t need to do day one, but it would be good if it&rsquo;s done soon.</p>

<blockquote><p>1) Register for the conference (for free, of course) with the code “[code]” at <a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/events/2016-minneapolis/registration/">http://www.devopsdays.org/events/2016-minneapolis/registration/</a> &ndash; this lets you specify food choices and shirt size.</p></blockquote>

<p>Speakers are providing the content. The absolute bare minimum the conference can do is give them a complimentary ticket. I&rsquo;ve heard the arguments around having speakers pay part or all of a ticket; I&rsquo;m unconvinced. Free ticket to the entire event. Period.</p>

<blockquote><p>Let me know what travel (flight, hotel, parking, etc) expenses you’d like us to cover. (If employers don’t cover travel, we’re happy to.)</p></blockquote>

<p>We&rsquo;ve handled this in an ad-hoc fashion before, so this time we&rsquo;re making it explicit. Sometimes speakers work for a well-funded org that&rsquo;s happy to support our community event, but if they don&rsquo;t, we don&rsquo;t want eat up all their &ldquo;training budget&rdquo; (insert rant here about professional development not being the same as training) or social capital for the year.</p>

<blockquote><p>3) Book your hotel room if you’re going to stay there. We have a very limited hotel room block we’re currently holding exclusively for speakers at the Hilton Minneapolis: [link] with an access code of [code]. The hotel is going to sell out due to most rooms being booked for a different event.</p></blockquote>

<p>The way hotel room blocks work is that you generally have to commit to filling 80% of your contracted rooms. I&rsquo;m always leery of signing on to that, since it&rsquo;s hard to know how many people will actually stay at the hotel; most of our attendees are local.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, this year another event snapped up a lot of our hotel&rsquo;s rooms before our courtesy block needed expanding, so I need to reserve the few available for speakers. Because of this, I&rsquo;ll probably sign on to a commit next year, if we have enough budget left over this year that it won&rsquo;t be too risky.</p>

<blockquote><p>4) Let me know if you’d like to do a Google hangout to discuss your talk. Encouraged for anyone whose talks I haven’t seen before! I’m happy to give feedback/input/ideas. No need to have any slides ready to have this hangout.</p></blockquote>

<p>Did this in 2015 and it helped a lot. Being committed to getting new voices into conference speaking means I&rsquo;ll take the time to help them give the best talk they can, and I&rsquo;ve been told that chatting with organizers face-to-face (via hangout) ahead of time helps lower stress for new speakers, too.</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>What you will want to know eventually:</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>This is the kind of info that usually comes much later. Just-in-time dribbles of info aren&rsquo;t my style. If I need to buy plane tickets, for example, I very much want to know the timing of any events that don&rsquo;t show up on the published conference calendar. I also want to know when I am on my own for meals (to schedule non-conference engagements while I&rsquo;m in town).</p>

<blockquote><p>Travel:<br>
1) The conference location is the Hilton Minneapolis in downtown Minneapolis, 1001 Marquette Ave South. All conference activities will take place on the <a href="http://www.hilton.com/en/hotels/content/MSPMHHH/media/images/floorplans/mn3f1.gif">third floor</a>.</p></blockquote>

<p>Yes, I actually linked to a floorplan. This hotel has ballrooms on multiple floors, and to make it even more entertaining, there&rsquo;s going to be another tech event in the building at the same time as us.</p>

<blockquote><p>2) If you are driving and planning to park at the hotel, let me know and I’ll get you the requisite number of parking passes.</p></blockquote>

<p>This is a nice-to-have for locals or others who drive. Parking is a pain by our hotel, but I can get parking-ramp vouchers our speakers can hand to the hotel&rsquo;s valet. However many get redeemed is what the conference pays for.</p>

<blockquote><p>3) If you are flying, send me your itinerary so I can have a driver meet you at baggage claim. (And if we’re reimbursing your flight, send me the receipt as soon as you’ve booked it.)</p></blockquote>

<p>I looked up how much it costs to have someone standing at arrivals with your name on a sign. The answer: not as much as you&rsquo;d think! I&rsquo;d never order that ahead of time myself &ndash; I&rsquo;d probably just get Uber and then spend 10 minutes on the phone with the driver who can&rsquo;t find me &ndash; but when conferences have arranged that for me, it&rsquo;s delightful. Removes cognitive overhead so I don&rsquo;t have to focus on that detail after a (sometimes long) flight.</p>

<p>In the past I&rsquo;ve booked the flights for speakers, but I&rsquo;m not going to do that anymore. For starters, you need way too much personal info to buy a flight. And this year I had the aggravating experience of letting a conference buy a flight and having it turn out to be a &ldquo;bulk ticket&rdquo;, which meant I was unable to change it. While I wouldn&rsquo;t buy anyone a bulk ticket, I now have a &ldquo;buy my own plane ticket, always&rdquo; policy, so I don&rsquo;t want to encourage the unwise practice of allowing a conference to buy plane tickets. Instead, they buy and then I have our finance person reimburse them asap.</p>

<blockquote><p>AV:<br>
1) Nobody is going to ask you for slides ahead of time. There is no conference template to use; rejoice! (Optional but recommended: adding your Twitter handle at least at the beginning/end and ideally on each slide makes it easier for people to tweet about your talk.) Lots of people will probably want your slides after the fact, and tweeting them with #devopsdays is the best way to distribute them. The conference will link to but will not host them.</p></blockquote>

<p>To organizers who think I&rsquo;m finished and happy with my slides a week or two before the conference: oh, that&rsquo;s adorable. (Nope.) And I detest the notion of making slides according to what someone else wants them to look like. (I&rsquo;ll still always suggest Twitter handles, since they make livetweeting so much easier.)</p>

<blockquote><p>2) You will present from your own laptop. You will have a confidence monitor in your line of sight so you don’t need to stand behind the lectern if you don’t want to. We will provide a speaker remote.</p></blockquote>

<p>There are a few valid use cases for a shared laptop (Ignite, keynotes), but in general, people like their own speaker notes, speaker timers, fonts, etc. As a speaker I&rsquo;m always prepared to speak off a PDF with no notes, but I don&rsquo;t want to require that of everyone. (Came in handy at one conf, though, where they had to run the presentation from the tech table due to cabling problems.)</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m wondering if &ldquo;confidence monitor&rdquo; is too technical. I figured it was easier to understand than &ldquo;down-stage monitor&rdquo;. And &ldquo;lectern&rdquo; is the actual term for the thing people think is a podium.</p>

<p>I neglected to mention that there&rsquo;s a stage or to ask if steps would be okay. I also forgot to mention we&rsquo;ll have bottles of water available; so many finishing touches to detail out!</p>

<p>If you do this enough, you have a speaker remote you prefer. We still will have one available for that intersection of &ldquo;doesn&rsquo;t have speaker remote&rdquo; and &ldquo;doesn&rsquo;t need speaker notes&rdquo;, because it exists.</p>

<blockquote><p>3) You will have a wireless lav microphone, which clips to your shirt and requires a belt or pocket, as the default option. If you prefer to use a wireless handheld mic or the mic on the lectern next to your laptop, you’ll have those as options.</p></blockquote>

<p>Maybe instead of &ldquo;requires&rdquo; I should have said &ldquo;works best with&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s possible to attach them to the back of a dress! And I could clarify that &ldquo;pocket&rdquo; doesn&rsquo;t mean &ldquo;pants&rdquo; &ndash; I usually go with a skirt that has pockets, and a hoodie works too.</p>

<p>I forgot to ask our venue if we can get Britney mics. I don&rsquo;t think they have any onsite, but if we can get them for not too much extra, I may add them as an option. They&rsquo;re my favorite, but they&rsquo;re somewhat of a specialty item, so I rarely get to use one.</p>

<blockquote><p>4) We will have an Apple lightning adaptor as the default option, with HDMI available if you prefer to use that directly.</p></blockquote>

<p>Frequent speakers tend to carry both VGA and HDMI adaptors, but it&rsquo;s always nice when you don&rsquo;t have to mess with that.</p>

<p>Props to <a href="https://twitter.com/mattstratton">Matt Stratton</a> for pointing out that by lightning I clearly meant Thunderbolt/DisplayPort. That&rsquo;s what I get for not having <a href="https://twitter.com/joelaha">Joe Laha</a> read the letter before I sent it.</p>

<blockquote><p>5) The screen will be large, high-res, and widescreen. Build your deck for 16x9 (unless you really like rockin’ the 4x3 &ndash; we don’t judge!) and at as high a resolution as you can manage.</p></blockquote>

<p>I would give more specifics about the projector&rsquo;s max aspect ratio, but at three months out right now we&rsquo;re still seeing what level of over-the-top AV the budget will allow.</p>

<blockquote><p>6) If you need anything unusual (like audio from your laptop, presenting from multiple laptops, presenting from an iPad, wired internet, etc), we have an AV professional as a member of the conference organizers, so just let us know; we can probably accommodate whatever you need.</p></blockquote>

<p>One time I was a room host at a conference and two speakers showed up with five minutes to spare; they wanted to use two laptops and there was only room for one on the lectern on the stage. I improvised by asking the tech table to radio Engineering for a cocktail round, but I want to head off these surprises if I can.</p>

<p>There will be conference wifi; I forgot to mention that. (I&rsquo;d still recommend never relying on shared conference wifi for a demo. Too many people doing a <code>docker pull</code> most of the time.)</p>

<blockquote><p><table cellspacing=2 cellpadding=2>
<tr><th colspan=3>devopsdaysMSP 2016 Schedule</th></tr>
<tr><th colspan=3>Tuesday July 19th</th></tr>
<tr><td>By 5pm</td><td colspan=2>Arrive and check in to hotel</td></tr>
<tr><td>5:30pm</td><td colspan=2>Walk through ballroom if you want to see where you’ll be speaking.</td></tr>
<tr><td>6pm-9pm</td><td>Speakers dinner at [restaurant]. Relaxation, chatting, speaker gifts. We’ll give you your badge and t-shirt here so you don’t have to worry about registration at the conference.</td></tr>
<tr><th colspan=3>Wednesday July 20th</th></tr>
<tr><td>8am</td><td colspan=2>Conference breakfast and sponsors are available.</td></tr>
<tr><td>9am-5pm<td colspan=2>Conference Day 1</td></tr>
<tr><td>5pm-8pm<td colspan=2>Evening event with Ignite talks. We will serve heavy appetizers and drinks, and you don’t want to miss Ignite. If you want to go out, we suggest you go out after the event.</td></tr>
<tr><th colspan=3>Thursday July 21st</th></tr>
<tr><td>8am</td><td colspan=2>Conference breakfast and sponsors are available.</td></tr>
<tr><td>9am-5pm</td><td colspan=2>Conference Day 2</td></tr>
<tr><td>5pm-??</td><td colspan=2>Informal self-financed gathering at [bar] which has decent food. If your flight doesn’t leave until later or Friday you won’t be alone, but everything is ad-hoc at this point. There are no official activities Thursday after 5pm CDT.</td></tr>
</table>
What questions can I answer for you?</p></blockquote>

<p>Totally stole this question from <a href="https://twitter.com/nathenharvey">Nathen Harvey</a>; it&rsquo;s so welcoming!</p>

<blockquote><p>Thanks,</p>

<p>Bridget Kromhout<br>
devopsdays Minneapolis</p></blockquote>

<hr>


<p><p></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/beerops">Katherine Daniels</a> wrote <a href="http://beero.ps/2016/03/07/on-conversations/">a great blog post</a> not too long ago about making space for the voices of others. If we want to benefit from the valuable contributions that new speakers can bring to our tech events and encourage existing speakers to continue, we need to support them.</p>

<p>And if you&rsquo;d like to see this conference approach in action, please <a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/events/2016-minneapolis/">join us July 20-21, 2016 for devopsdays Minneapolis</a>!</p>

<p>tl;dr: Giving a tech talk requires a non-zero amount of effort. Conference organizers can make it less stressful for speakers; here&rsquo;s how.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four Times I Said Yes in 2015 (and One I Didn't)]]></title>
    <link href="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2015/12/31/four-times-i-said-yes-in-2015-and-one-i-didnt/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-31T22:04:21+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2015/12/31/four-times-i-said-yes-in-2015-and-one-i-didnt</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Snow, sky, and frozen lake are painted the same color, pine boughs laden with white, icicles hanging from the eaves reaching towards the busy bird feeder outside the cabin window. The larger pine grosbeaks are moving in on the black-capped chickadees, a silent drama playing out in ruffled feathers and dropped seeds. Aggrieved, the chickadees perch sideways on the icicles.</p>

<p>At this point, you’re wondering when I started paying attention to birds. Well, Occam’s razor tells all: this dogeared copy &ldquo;Birds of Minnesota Field Guide&rdquo; has forgotten more about birds than I&rsquo;ll ever know. And <a href="https://twitter.com/gabehpc">Gabe</a> looked those up while I tried to take pictures of birds through glass and pondered the shadowless expanse that is the Boundary Waters on a cloudy winter day.</p>

<p>My 2015 is ending as it began, in the far reaches of northern Minnesota&rsquo;s lake country near the Canadian border. The cell towers haven&rsquo;t reached this far, but this cabin has internet (unlike last year&rsquo;s rental). Snowshoeing, playing board games, and eating Christmas cookies in front of the fire leaves plenty of time for contemplation.</p>

<p>The quiet of these few days casts my hectic 2015 into sharp relief. This year I <a href="http://bridgetkromhout.com/speaking">spoke</a> at a company&rsquo;s internal devops event, eight meetups, and eleven conferences in three countries (not counting two other conferences where I gave a vendor talk). By miles flown, I circumnavigated the globe more than three times. I joined the devopsdays core organizer team and put on the second devopsdays Minneapolis with our great local crew. I joined the Velocity program committee and read so very many talk proposals that I think I could now write (and possibly have written) them in my sleep. I changed jobs from one I loved to another that&rsquo;s the definition of exciting new challenge.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been a stellar year, and I&rsquo;ve tried to identify why: I think it&rsquo;s because I defaulted to yes.</p>

<!-- more -->


<hr />

<p><p></p>

<p><strong>One</strong></p>

<p>While I gave about six different tech talks in 2014, 2015 had just two main themes (platforms and distributed teams). Giving a version of my &ldquo;Docker in production&rdquo; talk in mid-January meant I became comfortable with speaking on this material earlier than I&rsquo;d thought; I gave it half a dozen times before OSCON.</p>

<p>After presenting at OSCON to an overflowing room (since apparently fire codes meant only about 500 people could enjoy it), I walked into the speakers lounge the next morning intent on breakfast. What I encountered before I could make it to the coffee was the O’Reilly speaker manager <a href="https://twitter.com/audraORM">Audra</a> saying &ldquo;hey&rdquo; in that unmistakeable &ldquo;there&rsquo;s a request coming at the end of this greeting&rdquo; sort of way. They&rsquo;d had a speaker with a crisis; could I speak again? Of course I said yes. (I asked the second packed room if any of them had attended the previous day&rsquo;s version, and to the one raised hand, I said, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m not telling all new jokes just for you.&rdquo; People thought that was funny, but it was just honest. I&rsquo;m liable to repeat myself. It&rsquo;s probably fine.)</p>

<p>As an organizer of smaller-than-OSCON events, I empathize with the turmoil that the unexpected brings. (&ldquo;Fuck it! We&rsquo;ll do it live!&rdquo;) I&rsquo;m glad I felt comfortable enough to step in (and it was exciting when the conference chairs mentioned my repeat engagement in that morning&rsquo;s opener). Someday I should watch both videos and see how similar they are. I did manage to stick the landing for the second one at exactly 40 minutes without a clock or room host. (I know leaving time for questions is optimal, but I do tend to run long. Like that meetup in Chicago when I took questions throughout and talked for over 90 minutes until the organizers said I was going to make people miss the last train&hellip;)</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Two</strong></p>

<p>Like I&rsquo;ve been telling the Bay Area recruiters for years, snow is a feature, not a bug. If I were interested in moving to San Francisco, I&rsquo;d have done so during the first tech bubble. I like my northern home state with our 11,842 lakes (even if they aren&rsquo;t entirely frozen yet this year &ndash; &ldquo;I wouldn&rsquo;t go out on the lake&rdquo;, said the cabin owners, though the deer appear to be ignoring that recommendation). As much as I value face time with my team (and I do!), I love being able to decouple where my employer is located from where I live. So when I switched from <a href="https://twitter.com/dramafevertech">DramaFever</a> to <a href="https://twitter.com/pivotalcf">Pivotal</a>, I went from an east-coast org to a west-coast one&hellip; but, happily, didn’t need to move.</p>

<p>After being on call for production infrastructure from 1999 to 2015, I traded in pager duty for more travel as a tech advocate for <a href="https://www.cloudfoundry.org/">Cloud Foundry</a>, a pretty sweet open source project. (See your <a href="https://18f.gsa.gov/2015/11/13/answering-common-questions-about-cloud-gov/">US</a>, <a href="https://governmentasaplatform.blog.gov.uk/2015/12/17/choosing-cloudfoundry/">UK</a>, or <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/auxesis/delivering-simple-clear-fast-humane-government-services-with-cloud-foundry">Australian</a> government innovation offices for more details.) I felt somewhat conflicted about walking away from full-time ops, even after I told <a href="https://twitter.com/littleidea">Andrew</a> yes. Do I no longer <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ilooklikeanengineer?lang=en">look like an engineer</a>? Am I opting out of being technical? Nope: still technical, but no more split focus. When I was working in ops, I was writing talks in my spare time and fitting conferences around work; now I focus on community and communication while still learning about tech, and relax more even though I travel lots. Ask <a href="https://twitter.com/0x74696d">Tim</a> who moved on from ops to do product for Joyent; you eventually stop reaching for your phone wondering if you’re oncall and left it on silent. :)</p>

<p>This change was a significant decision, but four months in I am so very glad I took the chance on something entirely new. (Helped that I went to go work on <a href="https://twitter.com/bridgetkromhout/lists/team-littleidea/">an amazing team</a> full of people who challenge me and encourage me to learn!) And working for a vendor for the first time means I&rsquo;m learning more about the business of software than I understood before, while advocating for open source means I&rsquo;m happy to share ideas with everyone in the community.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Three</strong></p>

<p>I had a lot of travel lined up for 2015 even before I joined Pivotal at the end of August. (One of my first meetings with my new boss was going through a google spreadsheet entitled &ldquo;Bridget&rsquo;s Kinetic &amp; Potential Commitments&rdquo;. Spoiler alert: most of the potential converted into kinetic, and I was home about 15 days between Labor Day and Thanksgiving.) So when the opportunity to speak at RICON came along, I was inclined to say no. The timing was such that I would still be jet lagged from almost two weeks in Europe for Velocity EU in Amsterdam and Cloud Foundry Summit in Berlin.</p>

<p>On the other hand, I wanted <a href="https://twitter.com/CloudOfCaroline">Caroline</a> to be happy, and it was a conference I&rsquo;d never before attended. I brought the same talk comparing distributed systems and teams that I&rsquo;d given at Operability in London, but since I was awake at 4am (the joys of going from UTC+1 to UTC-8), I revised it day-of. The talk ended up better for it, and I met new people there!</p>

<p>Conference protip: the people you meet or reconnect with at any conference are the best part. Even more than all the fun livetweeting or presenting or track hosting or whatever else you might get up to. And if you’re going to speak, the most fun per minute is in co-presenting (especially if you’re lucky enough to work with <a href="https://twitter.com/peterjshan">Peter</a> or <a href="https://twitter.com/caseywest">Casey</a>).</p>

<p>Oh, and my attempt to go home for a day between Berlin and San Francisco was foiled by KLM delays causing <a href="https://twitter.com/joelaha">Joe</a> and me to miss our US-bound flight at Schiphol. He still won’t let me hear the end of me “abandoning” him in Amsterdam and flying (via Detroit) right to San Francisco.</p>

<p>Connecting flights, like csh programming, considered harmful. I wish everywhere had direct flights to everywhere else, or better yet, I wish we had teleportation. Although then teleportation would be lossy and we&rsquo;d all be complaining about how we&rsquo;d left our hearts in San Francisco, where <a href="https://twitter.com/KarlTheFog">Karl</a> chills the air.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Four</strong></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be the first to admit I&rsquo;m the uninvolved sort of alum. I live a short bike ride from my alma mater and work in the field of my degree, but I never go talk to Today&rsquo;s Youth. Mostly it&rsquo;s that I&rsquo;m busy with a side of maybe-not-a-role-model, but when a former co-worker asked me to meet with a seventeen year old girl he coaches in sportsball, I realized the truth: I am conflicted about giving The Youth an unvarnished look at reality. Tech isn&rsquo;t the most welcoming place for, well, anyone. I know how lucky I am, and yet I still feel like I&rsquo;ll never be most people&rsquo;s Platonic ideal of a techie. I figured that talking with her would be a disaster and end in tears (probably mine).</p>

<p>And you know what? I was totally wrong. I mean sure, she&rsquo;d never heard of abstraction and had only the vaguest notion of what &ldquo;the cloud&rdquo; might be. (Obviously I told her about the cloud-to-butt plugin, because I am a Responsible Adult.) But she knew perfectly well that the industry and the internet are full of not-so-great actors, and that didn&rsquo;t worry her one iota. What she wanted to know was what it&rsquo;s like working in software. The popular perceptions steered her towards a picture of a lone (probably male) basement-dweller and I was happy to tell her that&rsquo;s nothing like my reality. (Even though I&rsquo;m on a distributed team and work alone sometimes, I don&rsquo;t have a basement. Which makes tornado season interesting.) She was excited to hear that software is a team sport with collaboration and sharing! Go go gadget devops!</p>

<p>So maybe in 2016 I&rsquo;ll make time to show up at the U’s Computer Science department and talk to the undergrads. At the very least, I could tell them to take a few psych and business classes. Like <a href="https://twitter.com/shinynew_oz">Astrid</a> says, software is made of feelings. I hear rumors of no distributed version control being taught in school (wat) but really I&rsquo;m more focused on the part where we might want to practice negotiation and clear communication and compromise and sharing. You know, just like real life.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Five</strong></p>

<p>You’re waiting for the no. And sure, I had to say no (see also: never moving to SF &ndash; sorry!), but this is a shiny happy end-of-year post, so let’s go with a technicality.</p>

<p>One last yes that made a big difference for my 2015… I said in 2014. :)</p>

<p>I joined <a href="https://www.arresteddevops.com/">Arrested DevOps</a> as a co-host in November 2014. <a href="https://twitter.com/mattstratton">Matt</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/trevorghess">Trevor</a> already had recorded a year of great shows, and I knew going in that I’d be able to chat with fascinating people and learn lots. What I didn’t realize is that at nearly every conference and event throughout the year, in whichever country I found myself, I would run into fans of the podcast!</p>

<p>Thank you all for listening; I’m glad we can share your commutes or flights and bring interesting conversations into your days. Thanks to all our guests and my co-hosts for making my first year of podcasting so rewarding. If you haven’t been on the show yet (or have!) but want to be, let us know! Looking forward to many awesome new episodes.</p>

<hr />

<p><br></p>

<p>Whether or not I mentioned you by name, if you&rsquo;re reading this, you&rsquo;ve probably made my 2015 better, and I&rsquo;m grateful. Thank you.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m excited for 2016. Definitely will be visiting Toronto and Bangalore and Austin, and probably many more cities. Maybe I&rsquo;ll visit you! Want me to show up and talk about devops, cloud, platforms, distributed teams, containers, or some combination thereof? Let me know, because I&rsquo;ve got to level up in <em>Flying: The Game</em> if I want to ever rate those nifty lie-flat beds. Plus, I love sharing ideas and hearing about what&rsquo;s working for you.</p>

<p>May your 2016 be full of saying yes to exciting possibilities! And hopefully more sunflower seeds than this bird feeder, which could lead to some dangerously underpopulated bird territories of the northern taiga if we don&rsquo;t refill it. I&rsquo;ll look into that tomorrow; it&rsquo;s a whole new year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let Me Google That for You]]></title>
    <link href="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2015/05/31/let-me-google-that-for-you/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-31T21:16:12+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2015/05/31/let-me-google-that-for-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Late-night after <a href="http://velocityconf.com/devops-web-performance-2015/">Velocity Santa Clara</a>, the crowds filling the hotel lobby bar earlier in the day have scattered. A few conference-goers with morning flights remain, ranging from speakers to conference committee members to attendees taking it all in. We decompress, talk tech, play games, drink, and eat ridiculously rich Nutella chocolate cake. We enjoy these last few hours with new friends and old.</p>

<p>After midnight, the discussion takes a serious turn. One pretty awesome guy who&rsquo;s been waxing poetic (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tomorrow_and_tomorrow_and_tomorrow">tomorrow and tomorrow and tomorrow</a>) in his <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mafia_%28party_game%29">Werewolf</a> defenses says, &ldquo;I want to ask women in tech about being women in tech, because you&rsquo;re the ones who know the most about it.&rdquo;</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/beerops">Katherine Daniels</a> and I look at one another before simultaneously saying, &ldquo;No.&rdquo;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>We tell the half-a-dozen (or so) men we&rsquo;ve just met about <a href="https://twitter.com/lara_hogan">Lara Hogan</a>&rsquo;s <a href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net/lara-hogan/2015-may-18">Mean time to &ldquo;women in tech&rdquo;</a> post, and explain that <em>well actually</em>, we are just tired of talking about Being A Woman In Tech OMG. Katherine is a web operations engineer at <a href="https://codeascraft.com/">Etsy</a> (a world-famous monitoring company that also is a marketplace for handmade goods) and is <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920039846.do">co-authoring an O&#8217;Reilly book</a> with <a href="https://twitter.com/sigje">Jennifer Davis</a>! I&rsquo;m a <a href="http://www.devopsdays.org/">devopsdays</a> global organizer and run <a href="http://bridgetkromhout.com/speaking/2015/containercamp/">Docker in production</a> at <a href="http://www.dramafever.com/">DramaFever</a>! We have lots of stuff we come to tech conferences to discuss, but if we aren&rsquo;t currently on <a href="http://bridgetkromhout.com/speaking/2014/velocity-newyork/">a panel about being women in ops</a>, then that&rsquo;s probably not what we want to discuss right now.</p>

<p>But why not? After all, we live it every day. We know so much about it, and you are asking us because you respect us and know we have things to say!</p>

<p>Okay, let me put this in terms everybody reading this will understand. You know how when you have questions about open-source software, and there are times and places and people to ask? There might be a repo where you can open issues or an irc channel or a mailing list, and the people listening to you there are willing to help. And even <em>they</em> will ask you if you&rsquo;ve read the faq, the README.md, the quick-start guide, the tutorial &ndash; because you&rsquo;re an intelligent person who can get started on your own before you need someone else to hold your hand.</p>

<p>And if you go on the dev mailing list where they&rsquo;re doing a deep dive into the regressions in the latest release candidate with your &ldquo;I tried the intro walkthrough and it was confusing&rdquo;, you probably shouldn&rsquo;t be surprised if the answer is &ldquo;that&rsquo;s off-topic here, and while some of the mailing list members might end up wanting to help you, they didn&rsquo;t all sign on for that in this specific context. Take this question over here instead.&rdquo; There&rsquo;s a time and place for every kind of question. Not every forum is appropriate for every question, because that would just lead to a chaotic mess of the sort that makes ops folks cry <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scott_Tenorman_Must_Die">tears of unfathomable sadness</a>.</p>

<p>There are lots of resources around learning about the issues affecting women (and other marginalized people, although this post is specifically about women) in tech. <a href="http://indecorous.com/imperfect/">Being an effective male ally</a> is a great goal (and that post, written by <a href="https://twitter.com/indec">Ian Malpass</a>, has plenty of links). I&rsquo;m glad you want to learn! You don&rsquo;t actually need a specific woman to walk you through it. You&rsquo;ve got this.</p>

<p>So wait, am I saying that the answer to &ldquo;I&rsquo;d like to make tech better for women &ndash; how should I do that?&rdquo; is &ldquo;pull requests accepted&rdquo;, by which I maybe mean &ldquo;fuck you if you don&rsquo;t come up with a solution on your own&rdquo;? Heck no! I&rsquo;m saying that the best communities are the ones where, in a clearly delineated and accessible way, people who know things reach out to make it possible for new people to join the conversation and get the help you need to start. But even in the most supportive of communities, you&rsquo;re expected to do your homework, and then ask people who&rsquo;ve opted-in to answer, in the place they&rsquo;ve offered to do so.</p>

<p>You probably wouldn&rsquo;t open an issue in the <a href="https://www.consul.io/community.html">Consul</a> bug tracker and insist that they walk you through launching your first <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/free/">AWS free tier</a> instance. You probably aren&rsquo;t going to watch <a href="https://twitter.com/jtimberman">Joshua Timberman</a>&rsquo;s <a href="http://livestream.com/devopsdaysorg/Rockies2015/videos/84882629">defense of curlbash</a> and then @mention him on Twitter, asking him to explain the command-line flags for &ldquo;curl&rdquo; to you, and then decide that clearly those infrastructure as code people are just mean and unhelpful because he doesn&rsquo;t want to be your named pipe to Google.</p>

<p>Respect for each other means we do our best to learn before asking for someone&rsquo;s time. You&rsquo;re busy, I&rsquo;m busy, we&rsquo;re all busy. And none of us need <a href="http://lmgtfy.com/?q=%22women+in+tech%22">lmgtfy</a> links to find out that &ldquo;women in tech&rdquo; has been discussed many times in many forums for years, and you don&rsquo;t need to require the women you meet to start from the beginning with you.</p>

<p>DevOps may be made of equal parts empathy and artisanally-crafted <a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2005/03/dont_shave_that.html">yak-hair</a> sweaters, but just because Katherine and Jennifer taught <a href="http://velocityconf.com/devops-web-performance-2015/public/content/effective-devops">an all-day training on Effective DevOps</a> doesn&rsquo;t mean that you&rsquo;re entitled to have Katherine teach you to knit at the bar. So why assume that she should use her limited stay in Pacific Daylight Time explaining <a href="http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/Othering">othering</a> or <a href="http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/Reducing_male_bias_in_hiring">unconscious bias</a> just because you asked? Maybe she wants to play <a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/8098/jungle-speed">Jungle Speed</a> instead! (Jungle Speed, for those who haven&rsquo;t played it, is like the pattern-matching card game <a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/1198/set">Set</a>, but with the addition of melee combat which may lead to broken glassware.)</p>

<p>&ldquo;So I&rsquo;m going to offend a woman I know just because I ask her about her experiences? That&rsquo;s pretty much bullshit, and plus, my friend/co-worker is fine with it!&rdquo;</p>

<p>Hey, when you&rsquo;re operating from a place of mutual respect and you already know each other, you can ask politely. When you&rsquo;ve just met someone, you don&rsquo;t know what kind of table-flipping sexism or web-scale data loss she might have endured in a previous job, and maybe she doesn&rsquo;t want to have those painful conversations with you until you know one another better. Assuming that an arbitrary woman wants to do the work of educating you about sexism is not the most effective choice, any more than assuming any random open-source contributor wants to provide tech support for you, on demand, on your timeline. This may be the first conversation you&rsquo;ve ever had about the experience of women in tech. I will need to commission a custom hand-knit hat to eat if it&rsquo;s the first conversation she&rsquo;s ever had about it. It may not even be the first conversation at that conference or that day.</p>

<p>So when should we ask people for help? First, start where you already have an established rapport with the person, instead of trying internet or conference randoms. I&rsquo;ve asked <a href="https://twitter.com/obfuscurity">Jason Dixon</a> for help with Graphite, <a href="https://twitter.com/julian_dunn">Julian Dunn</a> for Chef advice, <a href="https://twitter.com/sethvargo">Seth Vargo</a> for clarification on tricky Consul details. Key facts: I already could call them friends so I wasn&rsquo;t asking these questions on first meeting, I <em>asked if questions would be okay</em>, and  I didn&rsquo;t assume the answer would be &ldquo;yes&rdquo;. I tried to formulate reasonably informed questions so as not to waste their time. And if they&rsquo;re sick of those questions, I would be fine with them just saying &ldquo;this is the thing you should read&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Just because someone will probably have answers for us does <em>not</em> mean we&rsquo;re entitled to their time on our questions. (But I am grateful to all three of those fine folks for their generosity of time.) And if we actually know each other more than in passing, I&rsquo;m willing to chat more about this. If we don&rsquo;t, I&rsquo;ll give you my elevator pitch on <a href="http://bridgetkromhout.com/blog/2014/11/03/the-first-rule-of-devops-club/">why &ldquo;ops guys&rdquo; shouldn&rsquo;t be in your vocabulary</a>, as long as it takes less than three minutes and we talk about actualfax tech afterwards.</p>

<p>So yes, I have plenty of experience being me-in-tech. This doesn&rsquo;t actually make me an expert on All Women In Tech Ever, any more than I&rsquo;m an expert in all Docker in production ever. I can only speak to my own experiences. And I&rsquo;m happy to talk with you, but fair warning: I mostly want to talk about the wider Docker ecosystem. The <a href="http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/Geek_Feminism_Wiki">Geek Feminism Wiki</a> can help you out with the <a href="http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/Feminism_101">101-level</a> women-in-tech stuff, because I would much rather hear about your experiences with Kubernetes and Mesos.</p>

<p>When we respect each other&rsquo;s time, I&rsquo;m a lot less tempted to answer, &ldquo;let me google that for you&rdquo;.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noona Is DevOps Style]]></title>
    <link href="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2014/12/23/noona-is-devops-style/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-23T04:32:21+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2014/12/23/noona-is-devops-style</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In <a href="http://bridgetkromhout.com/speaking/2014/velocity-newyork/">A Woman’s Place Is at the Command Prompt</a> at <a href="http://velocityconf.com/velocityny2014">Velocity NY 2014</a>, our panel facilitator <a href="http://larahogan.me">Lara Hogan</a> asked me, &ldquo;So, how did you get tricked into operations?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Yes, it’s funny, but there’s also a fair amount of truth there. Most people I know who work in any kind of technical operations didn&rsquo;t start out intending to do that; it just <em>happened</em>. In my case, I got a campus job with the computer science department, and apparently giving root to undergrad student workers was a reasonable solution to being understaffed. (It was the 1990s. Many things seemed like a good idea at the time.)</p>

<p>Fast-forward twenty years, and I get an out-of-nowhere email from a young man who&rsquo;s graduating from college in a few months and wants to know how he can be me when he grows up. (Obviously he doesn&rsquo;t think he&rsquo;ll be <em>me</em> me, but, you know.)</p>

<p>Since I didn&rsquo;t follow a plan, I can&rsquo;t lay one out for him, but I can point to a few things that will probably help. Maybe. Possibly. (You realize that I’m pretty much just faking being a responsible adult, right? As long as we’re all clear on that.)</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Culture stuff</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;m putting this first, because it&rsquo;s really important. If you work in tech for even a little while, you&rsquo;ll notice that you have a lot of social and economic privilege, no matter your demographic identity, because you have more choices in your work and life than do many of your fellow humans. This means that you have a responsibility to, in short, think about other people, not just yourself.</p>

<p>Social justice is profoundly important in tech, just as it is in the wider world. Educate yourself about it. You may not read every article in every issue of <a href="https://modelviewculture.com">Model View Culture</a>, but being aware of the conversations happening around you is valuable.</p>

<p>There’s also an increasing likelihood that you may meet and even work with people who aren’t exactly like you, along one or more axes. This is a good thing. As <a href="https://twitter.com/aneel">Aneel Lakhani</a> put it in his <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gi5EkmWi3VQ&amp;list=UU3BGlwmI-Vk6PWyMt15dKGw">Velocity NY 2014 Ignite</a>, &ldquo;the single strongest signal that you have something to learn is that a difference exists&rdquo;.</p>

<p>So! If you act like a decent human being who considers others, you&rsquo;ll be the kind of person others want as a co-worker and employee. Organizations that value a devops practice also tend to value cooperation, diversity, respect for the ideas/needs/opinions of others, accountability without assignment of blame, and generally not being a jerk. There’s a great quote by <a href="https://twitter.com/jesserobbins">Jesse Robbins</a>: &ldquo;Don’t fight stupid. Make more awesome.&rdquo;</p>

<h2>Tools</h2>

<p>The one constant in your tools is going to be change. Mastery of tools is a great thing, but learning <em>how</em> to learn is even more important. You’re going to keep needing that. And as you’ve noticed, ops isn’t something they usually teach you in school (which is why we have <a href="http://www.opsschool.org/en/latest/">OpsSchool</a>).</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s my 10,000 foot view of the stuff I think you need:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Distributed version control. If you didn&rsquo;t get exposure to <a href="http://git-scm.com">git</a> in school or an internship, start using it for your personal projects right now. Yes, there are other choices, but git is the one you&rsquo;ll probably run into in a more startup-flavored workplace. Understanding branching, merging, pull requests, forks, and the like is a good idea. Centralized version control is not a great substitute (although you’ll find it at many shops).</p></li>
<li><p>Virtualization. The days of most orgs choosing to have and run their own hardware are coming to a definite middle. And even with on-prem or colocated hardware, getting the most out of your gear while allowing for flexibility means you&rsquo;re probably going to use virtual machines of some sort. When you start looking at private and public cloud, that&rsquo;s even more true. Get familiar with the concepts and execution behind hypervisors and VMs. Play with <a href="https://www.vagrantup.com">Vagrant</a>. Try <a href="https://www.docker.com">Docker</a>. Use your <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/free/">EC2 free tier</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>Configuration management. Operating at any sort of scale is a lot easier if you can treat your infrastructure configurations as code. If you haven&rsquo;t done CM on the job before, take a look at the simpler implementations like <a href="http://www.saltstack.com">SaltStack</a> or <a href="http://www.ansible.com/">Ansible</a>. Many larger shops are likely to be using <a href="https://www.chef.io">Chef</a> or <a href="http://puppetlabs.com">Puppet</a>, so once you get the idea, it’s a good idea to look at those. <a href="https://cfengine.com">CFEngine</a> has been around the longest and you may encounter that as well.</p></li>
<li><p>Programming. If you’re working in ops, it’s possible you aren’t going to be building out all the new features using the fanciest of frameworks. But if you can be comfortable in languages like bash, Python, Ruby, and Go, you’ll be able to see what’s going on in most situations you’re likely to encounter. (YMMV &ndash; there’s plenty of Perl and PHP still out there &ndash; but these are what I tend to see.) And a smattering of JavaScript (specifically, Node.js) would not be amiss.</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Learning</h2>

<p>So wait, what about all this school stuff? It took years. There were grades and tests and group projects. Which stuff will actually matter?</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Abstraction. The specific implementations of flow control or data storage in a given language will vary. You&rsquo;ll want to become fluent in the languages you use, but it&rsquo;s also useful to understand basic data structures (how is a list different from an array? Why use one instead of another?) and concepts (what is a no-op? what is iteration?).</p></li>
<li><p>Scientific method. You probably took lab classes where you proved that gravity works or electricity zaps or whatever. Here&rsquo;s the thing: the result was never the point. The point was teaching you to change one variable at a time and make careful observations along the way. When you&rsquo;re trying to solve problems in complex systems, you&rsquo;re going to be looking at a lot of noise. Trying to discern some useful signal is going to require you to pay pedantic attention to detail. You will learn to look for patterns while being aware that correlation does not equal causation.</p></li>
<li><p>Math. Calculus actually matters, as does stats. You probably figured you&rsquo;d never need calc again after finishing your physics sequence, but you will be excited to look at sums over time when you&rsquo;re debugging a problem looking at your <a href="https://codeascraft.com/2011/02/15/measure-anything-measure-everything/">StatsD</a> data in <a href="http://graphite.readthedocs.org/en/latest/">Graphite</a>. Statistics will help you comprehend your metrics and their relationship to your business needs.</p></li>
<li><p>Playing well with others. You know those group projects where your grade depended on other people and it was really frustrating if you couldn’t pick the people because they wouldn’t always produce usable work? Well, that’s an accurate model of the workplace. Choose your team with a lot of care; you want to know you can rely on them. And you want to be that person your classmates recruit for their future employers.</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Community</h2>

<p>You are not alone. There are many practitioners who will be excited to encourage you along this journey. Here are some places to find them. Many may seem exceedingly obvious, but I include them in order to show a complete picture.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Meetups. Even with zero budget, you can start meeting local people in your field and being exposed to new ideas. Go to <a href="http://www.meetup.com">meetup.com</a> and search for your local area, and look at the available tech meetups. There&rsquo;s probably a devops or infracoders meetup, or maybe something about cloud, or a golang meetup &ndash; whichever! Join, RSVP, attend.</p></li>
<li><p>Conferences. Your local community may have barcamps or unconferences. These will typically be free or low-cost with minimal barriers for entry. There may be &ldquo;open space&rdquo; talks, which means that topics will be chosen day-of by the attendees. There is not going to be an awesomeness test at the door. Even if you feel like you&rsquo;ll be out of your depth, just show up. You don&rsquo;t get partial credit for leaving a blank answer on a test in school, and you&rsquo;ll miss out on 100% of the opportunities you don&rsquo;t show up for (with apologies to Wayne Gretzky).</p>

<p>  The regional devopsdays conferences are low-cost, welcoming to newcomers, and an all-around good investment of time. Keep an eye on <a href="http://devopsdays.org">devopsdays.org</a> as they start to crop up for the 2015 conference season. Come to Minneapolis in July for the one I help run! :)</p></li>
</ul>


<p>The larger regional/national/international conferences sometimes have scholarships and sliding-scale rates, but your best bet for a free or discounted ticket is seeing if there&rsquo;s some way you can participate (ranging from volunteering to speaking). Conferences like <a href="http://monitorama.com">Monitorama</a> and <a href="http://velocityconf.com">Velocity</a> are wonderful if you can make them work for you.</p>

<p>And if you can’t make it to a conference in person, there is often a wealth of video either livestreamed or available after the fact. One good example is <a href="https://twitter.com/littleidea">Andrew Clay Shafer</a>&rsquo;s amazing talk about <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P_sWGl7MzhU">learning organizations and no talent shortage</a> at Velocity NY 2013.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Podcasts. There are lots of podcasts on devops topics. Check out <a href="http://devopscafe.org/">DevOps Cafe</a>, <a href="http://theshipshow.com/">the Ship Show</a>, <a href="http://foodfightshow.org/">the Food Fight Show</a>, and of course the one I’m now co-hosting, <a href="http://arresteddevops.com">Arrested DevOps</a>. And you can play along at home most weeks with <a href="http://www.hangops.com">hangops</a>!</p></li>
<li><p>Chat. A lot of people in the open-source world find IRC (often on <a href="https://freenode.net">freenode</a>) useful, and a lot of companies use team chat like <a href="https://slack.com">Slack</a>. Probably a good idea to become familiar with both models.</p></li>
<li><p>GitHub. As mentioned above, you’re going to want to have a reasonable grasp of git, and it’s a good idea to become familiar with <a href="https://github.com">GitHub</a>. While the &ldquo;GitHub resume&rdquo; is ridiculous (because many people can’t open-source their work and don’t have infinite free time), as a student you do have the opportunity to put some of your code out there. And if you want to try forking an open-source repository and contributing something, that will give you conversational material for an interview.</p></li>
<li><p>Newsletters. A good place to start is <a href="https://twitter.com/garethr/">Gareth Rushgrove</a>’s well-curated <a href="http://www.devopsweekly.com">devops weekly</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>Twitter. Not just useful for letting your apps be spammy or following your favorite public figures. In fact, I’d recommend making it your professional face. Tweet like it could be read by your next hiring manager (because it probably will be).</p></li>
<li><p>Blogs. Lots of them out there. Start with Etsy’s <a href="https://codeascraft.com">Code as Craft</a>, and you’ll also find great stuff on <a href="http://sysadvent.blogspot.com">SysAdvent</a>. And if you follow interesting people on Twitter and read DevOps Weekly, you’ll find plenty of blog posts to read.</p></li>
<li><p>Link aggregators. Reddit and Hacker News are popular at the moment. I find the comments to be of highly variable quality, and the content usually shows up on Twitter first, but you may want to at least be aware these exist. (Protip: if you’re going to be linked from the front page of Hacker News, read up on the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slashdot_effect">Slashdot Effect</a> and take precautions. <a href="https://pages.github.com">GitHub Pages</a> are a free and simple way to have a personal site you don’t have to worry about.)</p></li>
<li><p>StackExchange. You’ve probably used this to help with homework, but now you could consider using the free time you have as a student to answer some questions on there. You’ll help others, and it may also be a good way to showcase an area you understand well. (Note: I do not do this myself; however, I know folks who do, and who find it rewarding. I’m told there’s also a <a href="http://careers.stackoverflow.com/">decent jobs board</a>.)</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Career</h2>

<p><em>Finally</em>, you’re thinking. Maybe she’s going to answer my <em>actual question</em>. I left this for last because the other stuff is what’s going to make the most difference. Finding a fancy way to discuss your greatest strength &amp; weakness is a waste of time. Recruiters will start circling, but you will probably find that you’re more engaged and interested when talking with people you’ve met about opportunities you’re passionate to pursue.</p>

<ul>
<li>LinkedIn. Make an account. Connect to the people you know. Copypasta your resume onto there. It’s a fine way for folks to get an idea of whom to ask about you. Beware the recruiterspam and endorsements of dubious value. (I’m endorsed for &ldquo;awesomeness&rdquo;. Seriously. Amusing, but not useful.)</li>
</ul>


<p>Turn off the InMail if it becomes aggravating, but keep connecting to the people you meet. (Don’t do that annoying thing where you let LinkedIn spam your entire contact list, though. Write personal notes to each person if you’re sending out contact requests.)</p>

<p>The more people you meet, the less you may like LinkedIn, but it’s still a great way to help others by displaying your connection graph.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Recruiters. Take five minutes and watch <a href="https://twitter.com/petecheslock/">Pete Cheslock</a>’s Ignite talk <a href="http://vimeo.com/79377825">Recruiting Is Broken</a>. And then, resolve to take the time to meet people in your field yourself. You don’t need recruiters for that.</p></li>
<li><p>Resumes. GPA! Nifty interests or hobbies making you stand out! Your degree being in the exact right thing! Keyword filters that want JavaScript and you only listed Node.js! Yadda yadda yadda. A resume is a tool used to screen people before they talk to the hiring manager. Meet and talk to the hiring managers on your own, and they might want your resume for the files. Eventually. After deciding they want to hire you.</p></li>
<li><p>Interviews. Don’t stress out. It’s going to be fine. Do not forget that an interview goes both ways. Make sure <em>you</em> ask questions that show you are interested and curious. Read about the organization and have specific questions about their current projects or place in the market. Protip: you’ll likely have more fun in the revenue-generating end of the business, not in a department that’s viewed as a cost center.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Ask questions about the tech environment like &ldquo;where are your most painful areas of technical debt&rdquo; and &ldquo;can you run me through what your deployment process looks like&rdquo; and &ldquo;which <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single_point_of_failure">SPOF</a> scares you the most&rdquo;?</p>

<p>It’s very likely that instead of just the hiring manager, peers will also be interviewing you. They will be attempting to decide if a) they want to interact with you daily and b) you will have a net-positive effect on their lives. You should talk to them and answer the same questions for yourself.</p>

<p>And if anyone asks you to solve fizzbuzz or how many golf balls fit in a school bus, and you can’t stop rolling your eyes, you probably won’t be very happy together. :)</p>

<h2>TL;DR:</h2>

<p>By this time (if you’ve read this far), you’re thinking, &ldquo;Are you fucking <em>kidding</em> me? I have final projects, and exams, and internship stuff. When I am going to do all this additional homework you just laid out for me?!?!&rdquo;</p>

<p>Don’t panic. This is less a to-do list and more a set of resources; think of it as stuff to check out while you’re home for the holidays, after you run all the family’s software updates. It’s not even a DevOps primer &ndash; for that, you could read Matt Stratton’s <a href="http://www.mattstratton.com/tech/devops">DevOps: A Crash Course</a>. He links all the contextual stuff that I’ve not covered in an acceptable amount of detail during this whirlwind tour.</p>

<p>In short: if you want to do the devops-y stuff I do, trying out some subset of the ideas in this post is as good a place to start as any. Cheers, and do let me know how you get on!</p>

<p><em>(If you’re wondering about the title of this post, it’s a play on Psy’s line that &ldquo;<a href="http://seoulistic.com/korean-culture/what-it-means-to-be-oppa-unnie-hyung-noona-older-in-korea/">oppa</a> is gangnam style&rdquo;. Because hey, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Korean_Wave">hallyu</a> is awesome. And for folks who want to work with me at a super-fun international streaming video site, check out <a href="http://www.dramafever.com/company/careers.html">DramaFever</a>.)</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The First Rule of DevOps Club]]></title>
    <link href="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2014/11/04/the-first-rule-of-devops-club/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-04T02:25:18+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2014/11/04/the-first-rule-of-devops-club</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Heard last week at <a href="http://devopsdays.org/events/2014-belgium/">devopsdays in Ghent, Belgium</a>:</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m just in marketing, so I don&rsquo;t count.&rdquo; <br>
&ldquo;I&rsquo;m just a student, so I don&rsquo;t have anything to add.&rdquo; <br>
&ldquo;I&rsquo;m just a developer, so I don&rsquo;t really devops.&rdquo; <br>
&ldquo;I&rsquo;m not really in the devops tribe; I&rsquo;m just on the outskirts, but I&rsquo;m trying.&rdquo;<br></p>

<p>Whenever I thought to, I tried to assert both in word and deed that the speaker is in the club. They&rsquo;re participating at a devopsdays; they belong.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><a href="https://twitter.com/davemangot">Dave Mangot</a> gave <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/dmangot/the-cognitve-neuroscience-of-empathy-youre-a-devops-natural">an interesting cognitive neuroscience talk</a> at this devopsdays wherein he mentioned in-groups and out-groups, and said that from a neurons-firing perspective, we have a greater capacity for empathy with those we see as &ldquo;like us&rdquo; than those we see as &ldquo;the other&rdquo;.</p>

<p>This is an evolutionary characteristic of the human brain. It doesn&rsquo;t make us bad people if we think in terms of  &ldquo;us&rdquo; and &ldquo;them&rdquo; &ndash; it makes us homo sapiens, not that far removed from the savanna and the tribal group that protected us.</p>

<p>Going to a devopsdays, especially one with so many familiar faces from my tribe, is pretty awesome. It feels good to belong. And I gotta tell you, it feels pretty shitty to think you belong and then find yourself in an out-group again. Still.</p>

<p>Some of you are thinking, &ldquo;What are you talking about, Bridget? You have pink hair and spoke at like a dozen conferences in the last year and run Docker in production. Surely you never feel like you don&rsquo;t belong in the hipster devopserati.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Yeah. Except for all the time. Like when I&rsquo;m in a group of my peers and they casually talk about ops guys. Those ops guys are so smart. We need more of those ops guys, so we should interview some &ndash; maybe Python guys! or really brilliant monitoring guys! &ndash; and the guys we have will know more great guys to hire. Maybe even those kernel guys or other smart guys who contribute to open-source projects. Maybe a golang guy, or a guy with a really epic Proud Unix Beard. Because guys guys guys.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t have all that much to say about Being A Woman In Tech. I&rsquo;ve only got so much time and attention to spend, and I&rsquo;d much rather spend it on things where I&rsquo;m learning something new. (In a revelation that will shock precisely no one, I already know what it&rsquo;s like to be a me-shaped human working in tech.) So I&rsquo;ll direct your attention to <a href="http://modelviewculture.com">Model View Culture</a> or the <a href="http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/Geek_Feminism_Wiki">Geek Feminism Wiki</a> if you want to read nuanced, well-constructed writing about the intersection between feminism and tech.</p>

<p>Every once in a while, though, I need to say something. Last summer after hearing one &ldquo;ops guys&rdquo; too many, I tweeted about it:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en" align="center"><a href="https://twitter.com/bridgetkromhout/status/483350276540080129"></a></blockquote>


<br>


<p>In discussions on twitter, I pointed folks to <a href="http://jvns.ca/blog/2013/12/27/guys-guys-guys/">an informal polling of the twitterverse Julia Evans did last year on the topic of gender-specificity in language</a>. It&rsquo;s hilarious and you should read it.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/images/python-guys.png" title="Python guys" alt="Example from the blog of Julia Evans"></p>

<p>Right about now, we probably need to #include &lt;std-disclaimer.h>. I had my mind blown <a href="http://bridgetkromhout.com/speaking/2014/devopsdays-belgium/">researching surrealist art</a> recently, and learned that René Magritte saw labels as arbitrary. &ldquo;An image is not so wedded to its name,&rdquo; he said, &ldquo;that one cannot find another which suits it better.&rdquo;  So yes, I know, meaning is assigned arbitrarily. Language is mutable. Oceania has always been at war with Eastasia. Systemd is a floor wax <em>and</em> a dessert topping. We aren&rsquo;t all going to agree, and that&rsquo;s okay.</p>

<p>I cannot speak for all women ever, or for all women in tech, or for all women in operations. I&rsquo;m mostly just an expert at being me-in-tech. I can definitely tell you that when &ldquo;ops guys&rdquo; is the generic, I feel like I&rsquo;m in the out-group.</p>

<p>And judging by the number of times in the last twenty years that I&rsquo;ve had to pinky-swear that I&rsquo;m really, truly an actualfax sysadmin and would you like my opinions on FreeBSD for your NFS server instead of Linux (because lolTCPstack, amirite?), I think a lot of people&rsquo;s &ldquo;ops default&rdquo; is set to look more like this:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/images/real-ops.png" width="480" title="Real Ops" alt="Mitchell Hashimoto with a glass of wine"></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/mitchellh">Mitchell Hashimoto</a> is amazing and everyone should be paying attention to <a href="https://www.hashicorp.com">HashiCorp</a>. But when I got a still from <a href="http://vimeo.com/42882124">his Real Ops video</a> during Belgium&rsquo;s Ignite Karaoke, my immediate reaction was, &ldquo;<a href="http://www.ustream.tv/recorded/54697834">I&rsquo;ve got news for you. Real ops look like me.</a>&rdquo; (Patently untrue given the makeup of the audience, but it got some impromptu mid-Ignite applause anyhow.)</p>

<p>I thought that was going to be the only thing I said on the subject. But when the open space opening the next day had an anecdote featuring &ldquo;ops guys&rdquo;, I&rsquo;d had enough. I went up, took the mic, and told the audience of several hundred people (of whom perhaps 98% were guys) how erased I feel when I hear that.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en" align="center"><a href="https://twitter.com/zipkid/status/527103793717321728"></a></blockquote>


<br>


<p>I said what I always think (and sometimes say) when this comes up. If you are a guy, and you like to date women, would you place a personal ad that says this? &ldquo;I&rsquo;d like to meet a wonderful guy to fall in love and spend my life with. This guy must like long walks on the beach and holding hands, and must also be female.&rdquo; If that sounds ludicrous to you, then you don&rsquo;t actually think &ldquo;guy&rdquo; is gender-neutral.</p>

<p>Someone asked what we should say instead of &ldquo;ops guys&rdquo;, and I suggested ops team, ops people, ops engineers, ops folks, or just &ldquo;the devs and the ops&rdquo;.</p>

<p>So, yeah. There are not a lot of women in ops at the moment (understatement). If you want us to stick around, and if you want there to ever be more, choosing language that makes room for us to be part of the in-group is as good a place to start as any.</p>

<p>In later discussion, <a href="https://twitter.com/mindweather">Dave Zwieback</a> called me brave. Not so sure about that; maybe I&rsquo;m just foolhardy. I know the internets are not kind to uppity women with <em>opinions</em>. (See also: everything ever.) But I couldn&rsquo;t remain silent in that moment. I tried hard to make it not a direct attack on the speaker, telling him that it&rsquo;s not just him; I hear it everywhere, all the time, in the US.</p>

<p>I know I did make some people uncomfortable. I do not want them to have to feel that way; I know all too well how that feels. But I did want them to hear, and to know. (Some, including the very responsive and understanding speaker, gathered immediately afterwards for an impromptu open space on the topic, which was great.)</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve talked about inclusiveness in our conference community before. <a href="http://www.mattstratton.com/devops/hipster-devops-happens-to-the-best-of-us">Matt Stratton</a> and <a href="https://www.usenix.org/blog/navigating-conferences-unusual-attendee">Katherine Daniels</a> have blogged about it recently.) This week, I saw action along those lines. <a href="https://twitter.com/nathenharvey">Nathen Harvey</a> held an &ldquo;Ask Me Anything&rdquo; open space where any question was okay, and people asked about jargon and how to become a conference speaker, things that might not have seemed accessible to them before. I was really happy to see <a href="https://twitter.com/mfdii">Michael Ducy</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/chriswiggy">Chris Jackson</a> step up to the stage in Ghent and publicly correct themselves to ensure they were being as inclusive as they could. I can&rsquo;t recall having ever seen that before at a tech event; it heralds a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sea_change_(idiom)">sea change</a>. We are taking iterative improvement seriously in our culture as well as in our tools.</p>

<p>As for those conversations I had at devopsdays with the folks who thought they were &ldquo;just&rdquo; not devops enough? I told the marketing person that ops needs marketing; very few people know that operations is a thing that exists in the world, let alone aspire to be one of us. I asked the student for insights as to what was the most interesting from a fresh perspective. I thanked the developer for tools, because we in ops need tools. I told the big-company person that he belonged, and encouraged him to claim space and have his voice heard.</p>

<p>We aren&rsquo;t well served when our community is segmented into the hipsters versus the enterprise, the PowerShell wizards versus those who perennially believe it&rsquo;s finally the year of Linux on the desktop, the web-scale cowboy devs versus the ops chicks who hate MongoDB, and all those other inflection points where we differ from one another.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll do better to focus on the ways we are the same. All of us in this devops space are interested in improving our workflows and our interactions with our co-workers, no matter what our specific job functions are. We all want to be fast and flexible, well-informed and well-supplied with the tools of our trade. We all want to be proud of what we accomplish and happy in the company of the people with whom we accomplish it. We all want the product of our efforts to work well (whether we define &ldquo;well&rdquo; as features, stability, or both). We can use those commonalities to trick our medial prefrontal cortex into empathy with those erstwhile &ldquo;others&rdquo;.</p>

<p>The first rule of devops club is welcome to the club.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four Interactions That Could Have Gone Better]]></title>
    <link href="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2014/09/22/four-interactions-that-could-have-gone-better/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-22T22:50:21+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2014/09/22/four-interactions-that-could-have-gone-better</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I go to a lot of tech events, which means I meet a lot of people in tech. Most of you won&rsquo;t be surprised to find out that many of them are dudes, and awesome dudes at that. And way more frequently than I&rsquo;d like, I also find myself in the most <em>tedious</em> conversations.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re wondering why women don&rsquo;t attend the conferences, unconferences, meetups, or hackathons you enjoy, or why you don&rsquo;t seem to make meaningful professional connections with the ones who are there, maybe they&rsquo;ve been having these conversations often enough that they&rsquo;re tired of it, and would rather spend their time doing <em>anything else at all</em>.</p>

<p>So, here are four recent real-life examples of opening lines that didn&rsquo;t start off the interactions in the best way, followed by four ways I think they could have gone better. Not a comprehensive list, because none of us have that much time. :)</p>

<!-- more -->


<hr />

<p><p></p>

<p><strong>1. &ldquo;Are you an engineer?&rdquo;</strong></p>

<p>Those were his introductory words after looking me down and up and down a couple of times, and my impulsive answer was to laugh aloud. Nope, not my most empathy-filled moment, and I don&rsquo;t recommend that approach. I felt impatient to be fielding a question that sounded like an incredulous &ldquo;what are you doing at this industry-company afterparty?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Why&rsquo;s that so funny?&rdquo; he wanted to know, honestly perplexed.</p>

<p>I looked at his badge and said, &ldquo;It just is. <code>&lt;Name&gt;</code>, are <em>you</em> an engineer?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Um, yes.&rdquo; He seemed a bit confused. To be fair, he couldn&rsquo;t have been mistaken for anything but. He had a classic geek aesthetic, straight out of central casting. Nobody would ever question his plausibility in the role of Resident Computer Guy.</p>

<p>I pressed on. &ldquo;Has anyone else at this conference asked you if you&rsquo;re an engineer?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;No&hellip;&rdquo; And then he brightened, an idea occurring to him. &ldquo;But you&rsquo;re wearing a company t-shirt, and that usually means marketing or recruiter!&rdquo;</p>

<p>I lifted my badge and pointed to the &ldquo;Speaker&rdquo; line. &ldquo;Or an operations engineer wearing her company&rsquo;s shirt the day she&rsquo;s speaking at the conference.&rdquo; Gently, with a smile, I then made polite small talk about him and his job until the bartender could give me the water I&rsquo;d come to get. Although unintentionally hilarious, he seemed to be a nice enough guy, and we managed an okay chat of the Fight Club single-serving-friends sort. So I wasn&rsquo;t offended, just eyerolly on the inside (and okay, a bit on the outside too).</p>

<p>And then I excused myself to go back to hanging out with Team Etsy, who don&rsquo;t tend to ask such facepalm-inducing questions. I&rsquo;m extroverted and I like meeting new people at conferences, but when I don&rsquo;t have the energy to put up with possible negative interactions, I&rsquo;ll trade variety for a known-good. I don&rsquo;t enjoy interacting with peers who act like I am The Mysterious Other and Definitely Not One of Them. It&rsquo;s tiresome every time it happens again. Still.</p>

<p><strong>2. &ldquo;Wanna go to the titty bar with us?&rdquo;</strong></p>

<p>On my way into a conference hotel one evening, I heard the word &ldquo;devops&rdquo; coming from the bar, so I walked in and said, &ldquo;Hi! Sounds like you&rsquo;re with the conference; heard you talking devops&rdquo; to three guys in a conversation there. As opening salvos go, their response gets points for being direct (and succinct; they didn&rsquo;t even introduce themselves). I noped my way out of that conversation right quick, saying, &ldquo;no thanks; you gentlemen have fun&rdquo;. (It&rsquo;s possible there were detectable levels of snark, because what kind of question is that for someone you&rsquo;ve just met? I don&rsquo;t personally care what they got up to, but that&rsquo;s rather awkward. I&rsquo;ll leave it to the reader to judge or not judge their choices.) I then left the hotel bar and ran into a Twitter friend in the lobby, and while I was chatting with him, the three drunk attendees came lurching after me. (They were definitely with our conference; one was even wearing the conference t-shirt.)</p>

<p>They tried convincing both of us to join them, and (being sober) I made my saving throw to dodge an Axe Body Spray-scented attempted hug. I then excused myself and headed to my room, while apparently they kept following my Twitter friend and hassling him to go with them for a few more minutes.</p>

<p>(I&rsquo;m all for #hugops, but personally I&rsquo;d rather have learned your name or at least Twitter handle before we are #hugops buddies. And other women might feel very differently! You should have a verbal ACK that hugging is welcomed by an individual woman before you attempt it, or better yet, let her initiate any hugging. #hugops is a TCP-based not a UDP-based protocol.)</p>

<p>I never felt threatened or particularly alienated; I was heading up to bed anyhow. But if I&rsquo;d wanted to stay there and keep interacting with other conference-goers, those dudes were a deterrent; if I were a different person with a different set of lived experiences, this could have hit me very differently. It seems they&rsquo;d completely missed the point of the conference&rsquo;s code of conduct; I&rsquo;m pretty sure that wasn&rsquo;t the kind of inclusiveness it encouraged. And sure, there are much worse things they could have said or done. But when one dude said and did this relatively minor stuff, his two buddies thought it was peachy-keen. Not a sign of good peer review there.</p>

<p><strong>3. &ldquo;Do you know who that obscure sci-fi character is, the one you used in your slide deck?&rdquo;</strong></p>

<p>I know a fair number of conference speakers. Some need to hide before and/or after speaking. Some head right to the bar afterwards. Some thrive in the spotlight of &ldquo;office hours&rdquo; after a talk, engaging one-to-one with all comers. Many of us seem to finish our slides on the plane if not the podium. I haven&rsquo;t yet met one who puts stuff generated by /dev/random into a deck without being motivated by any context or reason.</p>

<p>If you want to talk about that TV show you love, don&rsquo;t open with a line that sounds like you&rsquo;re <a href="http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/Fake_geek_girls">fake-geek-girling</a> the speaker who just got off-stage. Because it&rsquo;s entirely possible that she taped the entire run of that series on VHS, can recite key passages, and rewrote one of the tie-in novels because she didn&rsquo;t like the ending.</p>

<p>Again, a nice guy. Probably meant well. But in those fraught moments right after public speaking, being asked if they understand their own slides is not a conversation opener that any presenter I know would enjoy.</p>

<p><strong>4. &ldquo;I didn&rsquo;t understand most of that stuff you just said about AWS infrastructure tradeoffs. But could you design my app?&rdquo;</strong></p>

<p>Design is a fantastic skill that I do not even remotely possess. Seriously, I could design you something awesome&hellip; as long as I could do it with awk or sed, and you&rsquo;re okay with it looking like <a href="http://nethack.org/common/index.html">nethack</a>.</p>

<p>This isn&rsquo;t even the first time I&rsquo;ve been asked if I&rsquo;m a designer. At least this guy didn&rsquo;t insist that I <em>must</em> be, because I look &ldquo;artistic&rdquo; (by which I can only guess the previous guy saying that meant &ldquo;female&rdquo;). (Yes, I have brightly-colored plastic hair extensions. I hire a stylist with actual taste to help me with that!)</p>

<p>The important thing is, when a woman says, &ldquo;nope, can&rsquo;t design stuff for you; I&rsquo;m an operations engineer&rdquo;, you should believe her. Or, you know, stop assuming that every woman you meet is going to map to the roles held by women you&rsquo;ve met in the past.</p>

<p>Also, I suspect nobody would claim to be in ops were it not true, since it would take about ten seconds to unravel such a deception; not to mention, most people don&rsquo;t even know operations is a thing that exists in the world. Maybe we need our friends in design to help with some promo materials!</p>

<hr />

<p><p>
<strong>So, how could these interactions be better?</strong></p>

<p>You are probably already pretty good at talking about tech and geeking out about the stuff you love. Hooray! Chances are decent that when you meet a woman at a tech event, she might be into tech too!</p>

<p>And hey, the above four examples could annoy people who aren&rsquo;t women too. This isn&rsquo;t specific to gender relations or intentional discrimination; it&rsquo;s about making choices that limit (or enhance!) the quality of your potential interactions with your fellow techies.</p>

<p>So, here are four approaches to try instead:</p>

<p><strong>1. Ask open-ended questions that don&rsquo;t make assumptions. </strong></p>

<p><em>Instead of asking her if she&rsquo;s an engineer or assuming she&rsquo;s a recruiter or in marketing, ask her, &ldquo;What are you enjoying doing at Company X?&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>She might have a hilarious table-flip anecdote about MongoDB or fresh insights into some Docker thing you&rsquo;ve been wanting to try. Give her room to surprise you; open-ended questions lead to better conversational outcomes in most circumstances no matter who&rsquo;s involved. And hey, most companies are hiring; if hers sounds cool, maybe you&rsquo;ll be interested in talking to them. Or if she doesn&rsquo;t sound like she&rsquo;s having fun at her current gig, maybe your company can poach her!</p>

<p><strong>2. Be as respectful as you would be to any person, regardless of their gender. </strong></p>

<p><em>Please, thank you, not interrupting (or at least asking if it&rsquo;s okay to page her out to disk!): you probably went to kindergarten; you know this stuff.</em></p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re thinking, &ldquo;I would never say something horrifyingly rude and sexist! I am unfailingly polite to women!&rdquo;, you still might be making women uncomfortable.</p>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t know a woman well enough to know how she feels about these things, I wouldn&rsquo;t suggest pulling out a chair for her, kissing her hand, saying &ldquo;ladies first&rdquo;, offering to protect her from amorphous threats, commenting on her attractiveness, or calling her &ldquo;madame&rdquo;/&ldquo;m&#8217;lady&rdquo;. What reads as polite to some might read as condescending to others, and definitely could be seen as setting her apart from the men you consider to be your equals. Leave the chivalry at home.</p>

<p>One place you can help, though: like the gentlemen above who could have peer-reviewed their friend, you can say something to the guys around you, so that they&rsquo;ll know that you value when they act respectful too. (Woman can say this stuff, but the guys who are less-aware are probably more likely to listen to other guys anyhow.)</p>

<p><strong>3. Talk about the event you&rsquo;re both at without challenging her right to be there or implying that she needs to provide bona fides. </strong></p>

<p><em>Instead of asking why she&rsquo;s attending or what she&rsquo;s doing there, ask her, &ldquo;What are you the most interested in learning at this conference? Are there particular speakers you&rsquo;re looking forward to hearing?&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>Tell her about something you&rsquo;ve enjoyed at the event and ask her what she&rsquo;s found interesting. (Yes, instead of first quizzing/judging her as to which track(s) she&rsquo;s attended, offer her some kind of conversational hook. You know perfectly well that the hallway track is a valid track! And that goes doubly for the Werewolf track.) This will help you welcome any new attendees, not just the ones who identify as women.</p>

<p><strong>4. Treat her as an individual. </strong></p>

<p><em>Address her as &ldquo;you&rdquo; and ask her opinion, not the opinion of a hypothetical &ldquo;someone like you&rdquo;.</em></p>

<p>She may be there representing her organization, but she probably didn&rsquo;t come prepared to represent 51% of the entire US population (or whatever the percentage breakdown is, where you are). Asking a woman you just met about Being A Woman places an unwelcome burden on her, one where she needs to play the role of &ldquo;Representative Woman In Tech&rdquo; for the 10,000th time instead of being seen as a person in her own right.</p>

<p>It would be pretty strange if every guy in tech you met were exactly the same as all the others. And that goes for women as well! Giving people space to be themselves allows you the chance to get to know them, which is awesome.</p>

<p>(And it&rsquo;s possible she doesn&rsquo;t want to be described with the noun &ldquo;a female&rdquo;, which evokes a Discovery-channel-like narrative of the female of the species approaching the watering hole, her calf hidden safely in the underbrush. Go with &ldquo;woman&rdquo; if you feel the need to point out the obvious.)</p>

<hr />

<p><p>
If you&rsquo;re recognizing your own past behaviour in any of the above, congrats! That means that you have enough self-awareness to realize that you might have inadvertently made a woman in tech feel like you don&rsquo;t see her as a peer. Awareness is the first step towards change, whether you become aware during an interaction or while reading a blog post. (The next step is trying out the improved interactions. Iteration is a thing! Perhaps you&rsquo;ll see better results!)</p>

<p>I love working in tech, and I want to be able to encourage other women in tech without a bajillion caveats about all the things they&rsquo;ll deal with constantly. Plus, if you create a positive culture that welcomes new, different, or marginalized individuals, everyone will want to work at your org. Which is probably hiring. Win!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[All That Sparkles Is Not Magic]]></title>
    <link href="http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2014/07/20/all-that-sparkles-is-not-magic/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-20T06:35:38+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://bridgetkromhout.github.io/blog/2014/07/20/all-that-sparkles-is-not-magic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On February 20th I emailed Michael Ducy, one of our local devops meetup organizers, and agreed to be the head organizer for devopsdays Minneapolis. The conference occurred July 17-18. Protip: 147 days isn&rsquo;t as long as you&rsquo;d think listening to Spike&rsquo;s monologue in early BtVS S6. (We&rsquo;re all nerds here, right?)</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I reached out to Mike Rembetsy who&rsquo;d done a bang-up job with devopsdays New York, and when pondering his helpful advice I realized that, like him, I needed a great team. If you were at the conference or watching the livestream you saw some of these folks on camera introducing others and facilitating Open Space; others worked behind the scenes with sponsors, on the evening social mixer, on all the details needed for smooth operation of an event. Donnie Berkholz, Marisa Brandt, Andy Domeier, Michael Ducy, Tom Duffield, Tony Notto, and Jeff Williams did a fabulous job!</p>

<p>Our speakers hit on themes of empathy &amp; inclusion, organizational communication, respecting commitments, the relationship between tools and culture, processing failure, the future and the past. I&rsquo;m incredibly grateful to all our speakers whether they came by bicycle from Northeast Minneapolis or by wide-body jet from Belgium. With humor and honesty, the longer sessions and Ignites alike gave us a catalyst to launch dozens of Open Space discussions. Most of the talks have slides posted already and video will be coming shortly; both are or will be linked from each talk&rsquo;s description on the <a href="http://devopsdays.org/events/2014-minneapolis/program/">devopsdays Minneapolis 2014 program page</a>.</p>

<p>At the beginning of the conference, I asked how many present were participating in their first devopsdays, and a vast majority of the perhaps 250 people in the room raised their hands. Based on everything I&rsquo;ve heard in person and read on Twitter, it seems that many people found it to be a valuable and thought-provoking experience. When Patrick Debois asked me to define a victory condition, I said that I wanted everyone to have a fabulous time, learn lots of things, take them back to their organizations, and be the better for it. I&rsquo;m hopeful we&rsquo;ll hear that&rsquo;s happening!</p>

<p>Our opening keynote speaker Sascha Bates talked about how &ldquo;hipster devops&rdquo; that excludes people isn&rsquo;t what we want to be doing, and on day two I got valuable feedback from a marvelously honest attendee that gave me the opportunity to course-correct a bit and try even harder to make sure everyone felt included. A little over a year ago I was the one new to this whole devops thing, this exhilarating space. I want to keep a gap in the conversation circle open to allow more people to join in. I&rsquo;m so excited that more people in my local tech community are interested in this cultural shift (and yes, willing to put up with all the jargon and in-jokes that any community amasses &ndash; perhaps all the goat and silo stuff amuses those from out-state).</p>

<p>In his closing keynote, Patrick Debois posed intriguing philosophical questions; one that&rsquo;s stuck with me (roughly paraphrased) is, when we up-end the apple cart and jump into something like &ldquo;devops&rdquo;, what have we lost? I think that if we pause, we reflect, we open our minds and listen, we can accumulate wisdom in striated layers, not washing away the old with the new, but layering upon it. In places, the foundations of older frameworks and practices may be evident, may peek out and glint in the sun. And everywhere, we stand on the solid shoulders of giant horses that may sparkle (I mentioned sun! Minneapolis weather was perfect last week) but definitely aren&rsquo;t unicorns.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
